e
e e
[Music]
welcome living Mana church family it is
so good to be back with you today and to
see all of you here we're so happy that
you've decided to worship with us today
and please let us know where you are
viewing from we want to say a special
welcome to you and if this is your first
time please put a one in the chat
whenever we're not here we miss you we
definitely miss being with the living
man at church but know that wherever we
are we try to tune in as well so we were
able to see some of the programming from
last week and so um and able to listen
to brother Terry's message last week as
well so thank you uh brother Terry for
the message and just for all of you
being here today and we just are just
excited to worship with you today so as
I always talk I start to miss some of
the locations but we have Sharice from
Virginia welcome good to see you here at
Living Mana we have I think that's
Rebecca from Pennsylvania welcome to
living Mana
church and they keep coming so if this
is your first time please put a one
welcome brother Terry from from
California I don't know how to is I
don't know how to say that new town you
live in but see uh Christina I think
Christina's first time watching so okay
Christina please everyone greet
Christina and Christina welcome that was
a one you said that was a one Christian
Christian Christian okay CHR Christian
yes yes all right welcome welcome
welcome welcome we have Derek from
Southern Cali
California we have John from Plano Texas
yes it is it is Christian and it's a one
welcome to living Mana Church Christian
just to let you know about living Mana
church we are a 100% online church we
have programming all throughout the week
uh we have speaking of mental health
Mondays we have mental health Mondays
and we're returning back this week we've
had a break probably about a three-week
break but we are returning this Monday
Dr Ricardo white and myself and we will
be doing our third part on depression so
please make sure you tune in for that uh
we are going to be starting true Health
Tuesdays back up at the beginning of the
year and we have a new addition we are
so happy we're going to formally
introduce uh Maria hmel to you but she
is a licensed nutritionist and a good
friend and I'm I don't we haven't read
her name yet but she has been attending
living man a church and she is um in the
queue in the queue for membership so
that will be happening here soon as well
so we are so excited uh to have her she
does seminars all around uh the world on
nutrition diet and nutrition and she is
just we are just blessed to be able to
have her here amen so we have that and
then we have our power Wednesdays which
is so powerful it is truly power and
during the week like because of the pray
and to hear the testimonies and this is
a prayer meeting that we actually pray
we there's no preaching there's no
preaching which is a blessing prayer and
testimonies prayer and testimonies that
is what it is and it is just a great
time to connect uh especially to God but
to your church family and to form
community and then we have on Thursday
Thursdays Lami Richardson is doing a
program a new program and testimonies
Thursday so you don't want to miss that
and that is hearing people testimonies
and and he's interviewing um a new
person this week which I'll be talking
about during the Divine worship service
um and it is practical Christian Living
and you know Mommy's going to to bring
bring the fire as they say bring the
fire so that is living Mana Church
during the week and then on Sabbath here
we are and there is even some
programming on Friday night as well we
have the um traditional Sabbath school
lesson that is taught on Friday evenings
and so you'll get more information all
of you first timers that have never been
here you'll get more information about
that and how to sign up to get alerts
and reminders of that programming that I
was just mentioning so yes as you can
see I have long I've been wearing long
sleeve T-shirts because it's
cold well depends on where you are in
the world but here in in the South where
we are we're definitely having a real
cold spell like we left California on
Tuesday I think it was 70° we landed uh
in Tennessee
and it was 25 de or something it was so
cold it was so cold and so um it's
definitely been cold here so I don't
know where you guys are I'm sure it's
cold if you're on that Eastern Seaboard
or in the midwest or here in the South
but if you're on the west maybe not as
cold and maybe in other countries it's
not cold at all but I'm wearing long
sleeve T-shirts right now so with that
said since I brought up the t-shirts um
you can't see it you can see Faith does
not make things easy it makes them
possible yes it's a good shirt yes
doesn't make things easy and I and I
guess I chose this one besides the fact
that it was a long sleeve t-shirt
because you know we have faith sometimes
we think if okay if we're practicing
faith that it's going to be an easy
journey and even in that faith faith
Journey there won't be any bumpy times
but there still you'll still be tested
even when you're exercising the faith
like it's going to be like you know
maybe you need to hold on tighter or be
on your knees more or just having more
oneon-one connection conversations with
God all throughout the day when you're
going through this journey um and so it
doesn't always make things easier but it
makes things possible so you always when
you have faith you always have hope and
you can always believe that what you are
needing or wanting um if it's according
to God's will he will deliver and he
will provide amen so that's the
encouragement for today amen and I do
see a question in the chat that probably
people are going to begin to want to to
know for themselves which is where do we
sign up for the convocation okay I know
you're going to talk about that whole
thing like yes yeah during I mean during
Divine service but maybe for those that
are that are on right now that may not
be on later well you should be on you
should you should stay right there don't
go anywhere you know they tell you when
you're watching something don't go
anywhere just taking a quick break but
yeah
um yes you're going to get all that
information in Divine worship okay there
you go there you go you could okay let
me let's give you some time and I wanted
to and this is what we're going to do at
Divine worship but we can do it twice so
thank you broadcast team for just always
being ready thank you so much for that
um so please scan that QR code and it's
going to take you to the registration
and where you'll be able to also start
booking your hotel um uh rooms as well
okay now what about people that that
can't scan don't know how to SC okay
that's what I was going to say okay for
our
gently older generation okay hopefully
you got some young people near you no
you can so get your cell phone I'm
telling everybody that get your cell
phone and point it toward towards the QR
code and you push the button like you're
going to um take a picture and then it's
really going to scan that and it's going
to take you directly this is a link
that's going to take you directly to uh
the website where you can register yeah
so just open your camera like you're
going to take a picture yes but point it
but point it you got to point it to the
QR code and it'll zoom in on the on the
QR code yeah it's going to like
highlight I think a little yellow box
around it and then you just push that
button like you're going to take a
picture and it takes you there okay so
technology is super cool but there you
can see we even have a theme for the
convocation it's the bread of life the
bread of life Fitz living Mana church
and so and you're at the convocation
you're going to be able to meet of
course we're going to be there I believe
we'll get to meet everybody yeah well
I'm about to say I was giving a list so
about to meet you're gonna meet brother
Terry sister Amar you're going to be
able to meet Dr White um he's going to
be presenting I'm going to do something
on on family and marriage haven't quite
on family and marriage and stuff like
that um so you'll you're going to have
some health talks as well um pray we're
praying that you're going to meet uh Taj
PB so praying about that brother Lami is
going to be there our prayer team is
going to be there LM lmlc kids leader
and they have a program for the kids is
going to be there and many many many
others so it's really going to be a
family reunion
convocation um yeah think family reunion
think that that's what it's going to be
like with the word of God with good just
good fellowship and time and catching up
and it's going to be fun yeah so
definitely be there if you're excited
put a one in the chat because we're
excited we're excited to have you and
I'm just going to go back to the scan
because I see some people saying yeah I
don't know how to scan it all uh we will
have a link directly to yeah if you
because we'll talk about it during the B
worship on how you can sign up to get um
either on on either on Mighty networks
you'll be able the same link will be on
Mighty networks the same link will be uh
sent to you if you sign up for text
alerts so those are the way as well yeah
um and then if you have any young person
or not have to be super young but just
any person who does know how to do the
links you can do that and you know you
can go back and replay this and you'll
still see it so there's ways there's a
variety of ways that you can do it
either get a reminder through the text
go to Mighty networks or just uh get
someone who can help you
scan the QR code yeah all right so yes
lots of ones that's great we're happy
that you're excited and we will see you
there but you're going to be getting
reminders and information every week
that we're on here up until then so
we're glad that you guys are can't wait
to get there yeah all right
so um we're going to jump into our
Sabbath school for this morning which is
uh the part three of the 144,000 study
the final part the final part all right
so we did part one and part two and that
was several weeks back yes uh and then
between part we're going to do part
three the next week and then we were
going to do it the following yeah we
just were we were in Orlando and then
yeah then brother's situation and then
and thank you for praying for our
brothers they're both doing well and
healing well yeah so thankk you yeah so
um we're going to go ahead and pray and
then we will jump into our study so
let's uh let's do that Heavenly
Father Lord we ask uh that as we uh jump
into this uh final study on the
144,000 and um and Ellen White's view on
it elen White's uh writings on it we
pray Lord that you would uh again give
us understanding give us Clarity give us
wisdom and thank you Lord for hearing
and answering because we ask this in
Jesus name amen amen amen all
right
um
so we are going
to uh let's see here all
right we're going to go to the
screen and uh let me know if you can see
the
slides all right let's
see
okay so um we're looking at Ellen
White's first video
to start this study off today um this
Vision was written out in 1846 it was
published in the day
star and uh what we're going to do in
today's uh presentation is we're going
to look at this first Vision because
this is where um this is where most of
uh
the writings on
or most of the um the initial statements
Ellen White made on the
144,000 uh this is where they are
found and uh we're going to look at this
first Vision in 1846 and then we're
going to compare which she says in the
book The Great controversy which was
written in the
1880s okay she talks about she talks
about the same events but we're going to
see um
how she describes it in 1846 versus how
she describes it in the book The Great
controversy so let's go back to the
screen and we're just going to kind of
lay out in bullet points uh what she
says and for those who believe that the
144,000 is a literal number so remember
go back and watch our previous two
presentations where we went showing that
the number is symbolic and we show this
strictly from the Bible right uh and we
use some ele quotes as well but the main
emphasis was used in the Bible but the
principal was built from the Bible from
the Bible okay and now we're going to
look at mostly just Ellen White
statements okay okay to to back up what
we've already established in the B so I
just want to make that clear because
people just tuning in for the first time
like oh there they go there there those
Adventists go using Ellen White to prove
something yeah yeah yes so we just
encourage you to go back watch those
previous two
presentations um
and uh and yeah so now um let's go to
the screen and here's how she begins
this Vision she says uh as God has shown
me in holy Vision the travels of the
Advent people to the holy city and the
rich reward to be given those who await
the return of their lord from the
wedding it may it may be my duty to give
you a short sketch of what God has
revealed to me the DAR Saints have got
many trials to pass through now We're
Not Gonna read this whole Vision um it's
not extremely long but it is it's it's
lengthy so I'm just going to highlight
the sentences where she talks the
sentences where she's mentioning the
144,000 okay okay so
um she says here in the same article the
living
Saints
144,000 in number know and understand
the voice while the wicked thought it
was Thunder and an earthquake so here
she's saying that you know when when uh
Jesus is returning there's a voice that
speaks the
144,000 hear the voice and know that
it's the voice of God but the wicked
think that it's thunder so again the key
phrase here is 144,000 in number let's
go back to the
screen she goes on to say by this time
the 144,000 were all sealed
and perfectly United on their foreheads
was written God New Jerusalem and a
glorious star containing Jesus new name
so here she says that the
144,000 um were sealed perfectly United
and on their forehead is written God New
Jerusalem and a glorious star containing
Jesus new name so remember all these
identifying marks of the 144,000 in her
first Vision let's go back to the
screen just to verify what this name is
the name and the New Jerusalem uh she
says in manuscript releases Volume 15
page 225 the seal given in the forehead
of God oh given in the forehead is God
New Jerusalem and then she quotes I will
write upon him the name of my God and
the name of the city of my God
so at tante the seal
mhm she says is the name of God and the
City of God written in the forehead this
is what the
144,000 receive according to this Vision
so go ahead and put a one in the chat uh
if you're following so far now remember
in our previous two studies we have been
demonstrating that the 144,000 is a
symbolic number it is a symbolic number
and so in this final presentation we're
looking at those statements that a lot
of people use to say Oh Ellen White said
it was literal and it all comes from
this Vision so that's why we're going
through this Vision right now so we see
here the 144,000 are perfectly United um
they hear the voice of God uh they
receive the Seal of God which is the
name of God and New Jerusalem written
upon their foreheads all right let's
continue
on uh as she's continuing on on and
describing this Vision she says then
there was a mighty earthquake the graves
were open and the dead came up clothed
with immortality the 144,000 shouted
Hallelujah as they recognized their
friends who had been torn from them by
death and in the same moment we were
changed and caught up together with them
to meet the Lord in the air we all
entered the cloud together and were
seven days ascending to the sea of glass
when Jesus brought along the crowns and
with own with his own right hand placed
them on our heads all right so now she's
describing here what seems to be like
the 144,000 see those who have been
ripped from them by death and so again
people say see the 144,000 is a literal
number it's a literal group of people
and they are alive and they see the dead
being raised okay okay
um she goes on he gave us harps of gold
and Palms of Victory here on the sea of
glass the 144,000 stood in a perfect
square some of them had very bright
crowns others not so bright some crowns
appeared hung heavy with stars While
others had but few so once
again so he says that the 144,000 stand
on the sea of glass and they stand in a
perfect square
okay um Angels were all about us as we
marched over the sea of glass to the
gate of the city Jesus raised his mighty
glorious arm laid hold on of the gate
and swung it back on its golden hinges
and said to us you have washed your
robes in my blood stood stiffly for my
truth enter in we all marched in and
felt we had a perfect right in the city
now what Ellen White does in this vision
is very interesting because she's
talking about our Ascension to heaven
and then just a few sentences later she
writes this we all
descended from this place down into the
City and with Jesus at our head we all
descended from the city down to this
Earth on a Great and Mighty Mountain
which could not bear Jesus up and it
parted us under and there was a mighty
plane so she's describing the 1,00 years
she's describing us ascending and then
descending just in a few sentences so
the vision is a rapid Vision right right
M
um reading on then we looked upon that
great City with 12 foundations 12 gates
three on each side and an angel at each
gate and All Cried Out and All Cried Out
The City the great City it's coming it's
coming down from God out of heaven and
it came and settled in the place where
we stood then we began to look at the
Glorious things outside of the city
Mount Zion was just before us and on the
mountain sat a glorious Temple and about
it seven other mountains on which grew
roses and lies and I saw the little ones
climb or if they chose use their little
wings to fly to the top of the mountain
and pluck the never flading fading
flowers and as we were about to enter
the Holy Temple Jesus raised his lovely
voice and said only the 144,000 enter
this place and we shouted Hallelujah we
bless the well bless the Lord Brother
Jacob someone that she said was going to
be there it is an extra meeting for
those who have the Seal of the Living
God I saw that there were tables of
stone in the midst in which the names of
144,000 were engraved in letters of gold
so now she says you know uh there's an
extra meeting for those who have the
Seal of the Living God in other words
this meeting is exclusive to those who
have the Seal of
God and that she sees the names of the
144,000 written in tables of stone so
these are the main reasons that most
people who think that 144,000 is literal
say oh it's literal see like this is
clear but what we've demonstrated in the
last two study on this the is if we go
to the Bible first and then compare
Ellen White's writings to the Bible I
believe we're going to see the opposite
that this number is symbolic and she's
using the 144,000 in a symbolic sense
okay so to summarize what we' seen the
first Vision let's go ahead and go back
to the screen here is the
summary the 144,000 understand the voice
of God the 144,000 are sealed the name
of the Father which is the name of the
father and the city in their
foreheads um the 144,000 stand in a
perfect square on the sea of glass uh
they are recognized by friends they're
recognized by friends torn from them by
death only the 144,000 enter the
temple and tables of stone with the
names of the 144,000 Okay so we've set
the foundation this is the first Vision
okay so what we're going to do now is
we're going to go ahead and we are going
to look at how she describes this same
scene in the book The Great controversy
okay which was written in the 1880s so
remember in this first Vision it's 1846
and she's seen this for the the first
time right and describing it for the
first
time this Vision was not given in 1846
this Vision was in
1844 but it was written out 184 in
1846 okay so now let's go to the great
controversy this is now written in the
1880s and let's see what she says here
let's go back to the
screen the voice of God this is the
great controversy by the way this is
chapter God's people delivered so it's
chapter 40 the end of the book God's
people delivered and she's about to
explain almost like verbatim the very
same vision but listen to how she puts
it in the great controversy the voice of
God is heard from Heaven declaring the
day and hour of Jesus coming and
delivering the Everlasting Covenant to
his people like peels of loudest Thunder
his words roll through the
Earth the Israel of God stand listening
with their eyes fixed upward now
in
1846 she writes the 144,000 right right
they hear the voice they're the ones
that are standing and listening in the
great controversy she calls it the
Israel of God so the question is who is
the Israel of God right it is all of
God's
people at this point in the vision it's
the living they are alive this is the
Israel of God right so the question we
have to ask now is
will there literally only be 144,000
people alive who are righteous at the
second coming of
Jesus I I don't know anybody that
believes that and the Bible doesn't
teach that right so we know that a great
multitude just from this outpouring of
the Holy Spirit there's going to be a
great multitude of people alive at the
second coming of Jesus who have accepted
him
right mm so the Israel of god let's keep
reading the Israel of God stand
listening with their eyes fixed upward
their countenances are lightened up with
his glory and shine as did the face of
Moses when he came down from from SI the
wicked cannot look upon them and when
the blessing is pronounced on those who
have honored God by keeping the Sabbath
holy there there is a mighty shout of
Victory so we're going to compare this
with where she says the living Saints
144,000 in number no one understand the
voice while the wicked thought it was
Thunder and an earthquake so in
1846 she uses the term
144,000 in the great controversy written
in the 1880s she uses the term the
Israel of God the Israel of God is going
to be everybody that is redeemed that is
living at the end of time right and that
is more than 144,000 literal people
144,000 literal Jewish males right okay
all right let's keep
reading she goes on to say uh amid the
Reel of the earth amid The Reeling of
the Earth the flashing of light and the
Roar of Thunder the voice of the Son of
God calls forth the sleeping Saints he
looks upon the graves of the righteous
then raising his hands to Heaven he
cries awake awake ye that sleep in the
dust of the earth arise throughout the
land and breadth throughout the length
and breadth of the Earth the dead shall
hear that voice and they that here shall
live and the whole Earth shall ring with
the tread of the exceeding great Army of
every nation Kindred tongue and people
from the prison House of death they come
clothed with immortality with Immortal
Glory crying oh death where is thy sting
oh grave where is thy Victory and the
living righteous and the Risen Saints
unite their voices in a long glad shout
of Victory and now listen to
this before entering the city of God the
savior bestows upon his followers the
emblems of Victory and invest them with
the Insignia of their Royal
State the glittering ranks are drawn up
in the form of a hollow of a hollow
Square about their King whose form rises
in Majesty high above Saint an angel
whose countenance beams upon them full
of benign of benignant uh benignant love
m
throughout the unnumbered host of the
redeemed every glance is fixed upon him
every eye beholds his glory whose Visage
was so marred more than any other man
and his form more than the sons of men
upon the heads of these Overcomers Jesus
with his own right hand places the Crown
of Glory
okay
so who forms the Hollow Square in the
writing it's the 144,000 M who forms the
Hollow Square in the great controversy
in
1888 it is all the redeemed yes those
that have been resurrected from the dead
and those that are living form the
hollow squares so then if we see that in
the great controversy she says that the
Hollow Square was formed by all the
redeemed but in but in 1846 she wrote
yeah that's 144,000
the only logical conclusion that we can
make is at the
144,000 and that great multitude are the
same thing are one and the same they are
the same group of people in
1846 when she's writing it out when she
sees the vision for the first time in
1844 she's writing out what she
sees in
1888 she's talking about the same vision
but now she's using different terms
right okay and I mean you see you have
to be able to to put that together
because of the biblical Foundation that
we were able to to prove absolutely
originally absolutely because if you go
by the Bible
only the 144,000 has to be a symbolic
group right okay now you you see what
Ellen White is saying here in the 1846
writing and the 1880 the 1880s writing
mhm now you're like okay these are the
same group right there's not two Hollow
squares uh it on the sea of glass it's
one Hollow Square and and in the great
controversy that one Hollow Square is
made up of the redeemed Saints from
every age not just the living Saints yes
they are the
144,000 but every saint becomes part of
that group some have not taste to death
were translated at the second coming of
Jesus but others are from every other
age this is what makes up that Hollow
Square so again here's our comparison um
go back to what she said in
1846 she said he gave us harps of gold
and Palms of Victory here on the sea of
glass the 144,000 stood in a perfect
square some of them had very bright
crowns others not so bright some crowns
appeared hung heavy with stars While
others had but few
in the great controversy she says for
each there is a crown bearing his own
new name and the inscription Holiness of
the Lord in every hand are placed the
Victor's palm and Shining Harps so in
1846 she says 144,000 stand in a square
they receive the golden crowns they have
um Palms of victory in their hands in
great controversy she says everybody mhm
everybody has a a palm in their hand and
a crown upon their head and everybody
forms that Hollow
Square so again there's not going to be
some in heaven without a crown that's
right some might have will be like she
said brighter not as not as bright which
you're just that's still that's
representing the the souls that we're
they're saved through our witness
through our yeah absolutely absolutely
all right so
um let's go back to the screen and we're
going to continue reading upon the
crystal sea Before the Throne the sea of
glass as it were mingled with fire now
this is the great controversy upon the
crystal sea Before the Throne that sea
of glass as it were mingled with fire so
resplendant with is so resplendant is it
with the glory of God are gathered the
company that have gotten the victory
over the Beast and over his image and
over his Mark and over the number of his
name with the lamb upon Mount Zion
having the harps of God they stand the
144,000 that were redeemed from among
men and there is heard as the sound of
many Waters and as a sound of a great
Thunder the voice of Harpers harping
with their Harps so what she says here
is that the
144,000 are standing upon the sea of
glass mingled with fire almost as if
it's only the
144,000 right only this select group of
people that are standing upon the sea of
glass mingled with fire
okay but let's see if that's true let's
go back this is from Heavenly Places
page 279 here's what she says here all
will be divided into two great classes
those who keep the Commandments of God
and the faith of Jesus and those who
worship the Beast and His Image and
receive his Mark Church state will unite
to compel all to receive the mark of the
beast yet the people of God will not
receive
it the people the prophet beholds them
that had gotten the victory over the
Beast and over his image and over his
Mark and over the number of his name
stand on a sea of glass having the harps
of God so what she says at the end of
time there is only two groups of people
not three groups of people what do I
mean by that many of us think there are
three groups of people there's the
wicked there's a great multitude and
then there's
144,000 she says there's only two
groups those who are the wicked and
those who had gotten the victory over
the Beast over his image and over his
Mark who will stand upon the sea of
glass that is the 144,000 it's not three
groups it's not 144,000 who then go out
to speak to a great multitude no
the entire great multitude that will be
saved when Jesus
comes particularly among those that are
alive that entire
group is symbolic of the
144,000 and then when the dead are
raised they all become a part we all
enter the cloud together together it's
all the same group it's only two groups
of
people I I I've said this before but I
just think the proper understanding of
this uh
teaching in the Bible is just to the
proper understanding helps you to have
hope because without it I just feel like
if you really believe that it's a
literal number it's just it's hard to
believe yeah that and yeah and again
almost like a lottery ticket I mean you
know what I'm saying like you have
million of people of winning out of that
it's like it's hard it's like so why Try
yeah and this is this again is what
drives
this understanding not for everybody but
for a lot of people this understanding
drives a CRA the crab in the barrel
mentality yeah right the crab in the
barrel mentality is I got to pull other
people down because so I can I I need to
be at the top of this group and
therefore I need to find as much
possible as much wrong with everybody
else's possible to comfort my own self
that I am truly one of that unique
special you know the the the special
seals and I gotta make right and I got
to make up sins that are not even in the
ten commandments so that I can appear to
be I mean not God we're talking about
God God's not fooled and he's not
whatever but people in their minds are
thinking like I'm going to try to appear
more holy Yeah by adding to the Ten
Commandments yeah I'm just GNA you know
make my own standards make my own rules
and say see look how many people aren't
and what happens is when you when you
have this approach
it it can actually do psychological
damage to you absolutely again not for
everyone that believes this I'm not
saying that at all but what I'm saying
is that many who believe this are living
that crab they have that
crab mentality I got to pull others down
to pull myself up I would say yes and
whole and whole Ministries are based on
this right and I agree and with you 100%
I would say
that when we believe that we have that
when we believe that we have to raise
these standards So High um that it's
like I would say not even humanly
possible to to keep all the time or
whatever or it's not even God telling us
that that's what you have to do
that it does make you emotionally not
stable or just mentally not as healthy
as you should be um because you're
always be basically it cause a lot
causes a lot of anxiety you're always
anxious because you're always not you're
not you're definitely not U having peace
and confidence in your own salvation and
then you're always judging everybody
else exactly and that's very unfortunate
and it's not just in the Adventist
Church no no no it's and the other
Church do it not necessarily for the
same misunderstanding of this Doctrine
but it's still that same you know Satan
is not not unique to try to mess people
up on just one particular Doctrine in
other churches it'll be a different
thing but it's still that same for other
churches it's the eternally burning hell
there you go there it is and and yeah
God does have a standard right right but
remember what the Pharisees and sadu
Sadducees did right
they created so many you can't walk on
the Sabbath all these different
rules right and let me go back to the in
in the other churches it's if you know
if God Burns a wicked forever and ever
then yeah I gotta you know do the best
that I can to be better than whoever is
going to be lost right it's still a fear
motivated right approach to to to the
Bible with just anxiety and just yeah
anxious anxious relationship with God
that's not what he wants no he does want
that not at all that's not exercising
faith and it's not bringing peace and
that's what he came to bring us yep yep
he came to bring us peace yep all right
let's go back to the screen and we're
going to keep reading we're going to
keep looking at this comparison between
uh between 18 uh the 1846 writing and
the great controversy in 1880s so
standing on the sea of glass this is
testimonies Volume 5 page
485 continuing on that theme of the sea
of glass she says but when we with all
the redeemed shall stand upon the sea of
glass with harps of gold and crowns of
glory and before us the immensity of
Eternity then we shall see how short was
the waiting period of pration she puts a
quote in there note that she says when
we with all the redeemed shall stand
upon the sea of glass with the harps of
gold and crowns of
Glory if it's the 144,000 that stand
upon the sea of glass but here she says
we with all the redeemed stand on the
sea of glass then 144,000 standing on
the sea of glass is the same as the
great multitude it's one group it's one
group let me keep reading um she says
here in Patriarchs and Prophets page 289
this song and the great Deliverance
which which it commemorates made an
impression never to be faced from the
memory of the Hebrew people again from
age to age it was echoed by the prophets
and singers of Israel testifying that
Jehovah is the strength and deliverance
of those who trust in him that song does
not belong to the Jewish people alone it
points forward to the destruction of all
the foes of righteousness and the final
victory of the Israel of God the prophet
of patmas beholds the white robed
multitude the
white robed multitude that have gotten
the victory stand on the sea of glass
mingle with fire having the harps of God
and they sing the song of Moses the
servant of God and the song of the Lamb
so the question now is who sings the
song of Moses who sings the song of the
Lamb they are the same group as the
144,000 they the same group that I
gotten the victory all of these she's
actually
using uh um verses that apply to the
great multitude or to the 144,000 and
applying it to the group of to the great
multitude or to the 144,000 she's using
these verses
interchangeably um note what she says
here God grant
and I think this is a continuation God
grant with all the redeemed you may have
God grant that with all the redeemed you
may have the Glorious privilege of
standing upon the sea of glass and
walking the streets of gold God grant
that at the time there may be given to
your hand a harp of gold and and that as
you sweep its strings all Heaven May
ReSound with your notes of joy and
praise and they sing the song of mos and
they and and they sing A New Song Before
the Throne a song which no man can learn
save the 140 and 4,000 it is a song of
Moses and of the Lamb a song of
Deliverance none but the 144,000 can
learn that song for it is a song of
their
experience an experience that no other
such company have ever had these are
they which follow the lamb whichsoever
he goes these have been translated from
the Earth from among the living and are
counted as the first fruits unto God and
to the lamb these are they which came
out of Great Tribulation they that have
passed the time of trouble such as never
was since there was a nation they have
endured the anguish of the time of
Jacob's trouble they have stood without
an intercessor through the final
outpouring of God's judgment so again
here she's talking about this great
multitude that I mean the 144,000 that
are going to sing this song of Moses but
in our previous studies what do we see
about who sings the
song Those who sing the
song is all the redeemed right and then
she says I have the question quote
coming up here but she says angels can
join in the song but they cannot sing it
from experience right so the this the
the distinction here is not that some of
the redeemed can sing it but others of
the redeemed can't sing it the Angels
can't sing it it's the Angels can't sing
it because they have never gone situ
exactly so Ellen White is now in the
great controversy talking about those
who' have gone through this time of
trouble and I want you to note what she
says in this next statement and we have
a question just because I know
Christian's a first
time um viewer and she says is that why
the fearful in Revelation 21:8 are part
of the group that go into the Lake of
Fire yeah okay that's that's good the
fearful a lot of people are serving God
out of the wrong kind of fear right it's
not the healthy fear it's not the
reverential fear it's a fear that is
based on carnal fear versus a fear that
is based on love right right okay so let
me go ahead and read but they have been
delivered for they have watched their
robes and made them white in the blood
of the lamb in their mouth was found no
God for they without fought Before the
Throne of
God she goes on to say they have seen
the Earth wasted and famine and
pestilence the sun power the sun having
power to Scorch men so at first it seems
like she's saying the 144,000 are the
people only a Lial group group of people
who have gone through this time of
trouble but in the very next paragraph
here's what the very next paragraph she
says in all ages the savior's chosen
have been educated and disciplined in
the school of trial they walked in
narrow paths on the earth they were
purified in the furnace of
Affliction for Jesus sake they endured
opposition hatred calumny they followed
him through conflict sore they endured
self- Deni self-denial and experienced
bitter disappointments by their own
painful experiences they have learned
the evil of sin its power its guilt its
woe and they look upon it with abor a
sense of the infinite sacrifice made of
its cure humbles them in their own sight
and fills their heart with gratitude and
praise which those who have never fallen
cannot
[Music]
appreciate note how she's describing why
this is the experience with 144,000
right those who have never
fallen so who is that that's not any of
us humans that's right it's it's the
Angels it's people I mean it's the it's
the beings of other plan they've never
fallen they can't experience they have
not been through a time of trouble the
song wouldn't mean anything I I don't
say it wouldn't mean well it wouldn't
mean anything if they didn't ever had
that personal experience like being a
sinner needing Jesus being saved by
grace like they don't understand that
exactly it's just like when we're in
church and you've you you're singing a
song that like just really touches you
because you've been through something y
it's like you sing it in a different way
you feel it in a different way and
here's the key thing when John looks at
the great
multitude and ask a question who are
these the answer comes back these are
they which came out of Great
Tribulation John literally tells us this
is the great multitude m MH it's not the
144 it's not 144,000 literal people only
that came out of Great Tribulation it's
every one of them that have come out of
Great Tribulation right right all the
redeemed
those who have never fallen don't know
that experience that's why angels can
sing the song but they can't sing it
from experience she con she concludes
this section let's go back to the screen
she says The Heirs of God have come from
Garretts HS from dungeons from scaffolds
from Mountains from deserts from the
caves of the Earth from the caverns of
the Sea on the earth they were destitute
Afflicted uh tormented Millions went
down to the Grave loaded with infamy
because they steadfastly refused to
yield to the deceptive claims of Satan
by human tribunals they were judged the
violence of criminals but now God
himself is Judge and then she says um
they are no longer last two sentences in
this quote they are no longer feeble
afflicted scattered and oppressed
henceforth there to ever be with the
Lord they stand Before the Throne clad
in richer robes than the most than most
honored of the Earth have ever worn so
who are these standing Before the Throne
she just described them this is the
great multitude right this is the
144,000 right this is the same group of
people when you hear the term 144,000
you ought to be thinking the redeemed
that's it the redeemed red will will the
144,000 be translated without seeing
death yes yes why because they are part
of the redeemed will there be those who
have died there's one place and I
actually forgot to bring this uh and I
think I mentioned it in in a in a
previous
study but Ellen White talks about a lady
who had died and she
said this I saw this woman would come up
in the first resurrection and that she
would be sealed among the 144,000 she's
clearly stating here that this woman who
died would be part of the 144,000 yeah
so it's not a a living it's not a
symbolic living number there's a good
question too I'm somebody's asking could
the 144,000 still be the symbolic
representation of those and that's why
don't that's what I was answering okay
okay didn't say you answering it why
yeah okay I saw it I saw it s p i saw it
um okay so let's go back let's go back
uh to the screen and here's another
statement from Ellen White April uh
April 17th 1894 but remember that
everyone who shall be found with the
wedding garment on will have come out of
Great
Tribulation everyone every not 144,000
literal people Everyone that shall be
found with the wedding garment on will
have come out of Great Tribulation yes
SDA pink uh Mrs Hastings I don't know
who Mrs Hastings is but that's the name
Mrs Hastings Mrs Hastings yeah I was
going to ask if someone had that
reference but yeah yeah
good now here comes here comes a
bombshell y'all here comes a bombshell
ready here's what elen white says in
1909 paragraph 6 um uh letters and
manuscripts 24 here's what she
says the seal given in the forehead is
God New Jerusalem I will upon him the
name of my God and the name of the city
of my God only those who receive the
Seal of the Living God will have the
passport through the gates of the holy
city well how many how many people need
passports to get into the holy city is
it just a few people like select people
that need passports or does everyone
need a passport everybody needs a
passport everybody needs a passport to
get into the Kingdom of Heaven M that
passport is a seal of God yes she just
said only those who receive the Seal of
the Living God will have the passport
through the gates of the holy city so if
the
144,000 is literal meaning only 144,000
receive the Seal of
God then how does everybody else get
into heaven they don't they don't
because they don't have a passport let
me keep
reading many who take upon themselves in
fact no I'm just going to skip this part
let me let me go to the next
Slide John saw a lamb on Mount Zion and
with him 144,000 having his father's
name written in their foreheads they
bore the Signet of Heaven they reflected
the image of God they were full of the
light and the glory of the Holy One if
we would have the image and subscription
of God upon us we must separate from all
iniquity so the image and subscription
of God is the Seal of God mhm
right all right here we go
y'all here we
go um Rebecca I think you're talking
about the martyrs there uh with the thin
with the red trim on their garments the
blood uh I think that is a reference to
the martyrs if I remember
correctly but uh check this
out all who are found worthy to be
counted as the me members of the family
of God in heaven will recognize one
another as Sons and Daughters of God
that's from selected messages page
259 now this is from review and Herald
July 19th
1892 the family
name the family is named after the
father those who enter the Heavenly
Mansions will have the name of the
father and the name of the city of God
written in their foreheads they will
bear the Divine subscript
subscription
superscription and be partakers of the
divine nature having escaped the
corruption that is in the world through
lust all right
y'all what is the family
name that we just read about
here the family name she just said is
named after the father and then she
literally says it's the name of the
father and the name of the city of the
go of their God written in their
foreheads
all who enter Heaven Must Have the
family
name are there only going to be 144,000
people literally that have the family
name but then everybody else is just
like step kids or
no no
no the family
name is given to every individual that
enters Heaven MH it is is the passport
to Heaven you cannot enter without that
name written in the forehead you cannot
enter without that
seal and therefore the seal will be
given to the living at Jesus's coming
but it must also be given to the Dead
who are resurrected because they too
need a passport
right there will be no
illegal immigration in
heaven right everybody that's coming in
will come in because they have been born
again right they're not not coming in
based on color not not coming in based
on well you're not one of they're not
coming those who who enter in enter in
because they have been born again every
being in the Kingdom of Heaven
to get there must have the Seal of God
must
be
redeemed and have the name of God
written in their forehead which we have
just seen over and over again is the
Seal of God and who is the Seal of God
given to it's given to the 144,000 is
that 144,000 literal no it must be
symbolic
right we have no other choice but to
understand this as a symbolic number
because according to Ellen White all the
redeemed have the family name of
God all the redeemed have the name of
God written in their
foreheads meaning all the redeemed are
sealed not just a small group of people
all the redeemed are sealed here's what
she says signs of the times November 1st
1899 in the issue of the great contest
two parties are developed those who
worship the Beast and the image and
receive his Mark and those who receive
the Seal of the Living God who have the
father's name written in their foreheads
this is not a visible
Mark
right again it's pretty clear it's
pretty clear that's a crazy picture
sorry y'all AI is that ai ai just did
these pictures for me that was a crazy
picture but I I liked that picture yeah
yeah crazy in a good way okay yeah I
like that picture so this is why
Revelation
22: 3 and 4 literally says this there
shall be no more curse but the Throne of
God and of the Lamb shall be in it and
his servants Shall Serve him and they
shall see his face and his name shall be
in their
foreheads wait
what revelation 22 says his name shall
be in their
foreheads every individual this is what
it's talking about in revelation 22 it's
not talking about 44,000 special
people every one of the redeemed the
servants
[Music]
mhm will have his name written in their
foreheads to me this is this is absolute
conclusion that the 144,000 is the same
as the
redeemed yes all right so let's let's
look at a few more things I know how
much more time we have we have five more
minutes five more minutes can you do
that okay uh how about I give you 10 15
15 how about 10 10 I can give you 10
okay 10
minutes all right um so let's go back to
the screen and let's go back to the
statement as we were about to enter the
Holy Temple Jesus raised his lovely
voice and said only the 144,000 into
this place and we shouted Allelujah and
I'll admit this one when I you know
every time I've read this after what
have been like man that that's a
difficult it's kind of like Paul's
writing some things are hard to be
understood and listen in every subject
that we deal with their verses and texts
and statements that we're like okay how
do we harmonize this but if we look at
this carefully I think we will see that
it is the same issue that we're dealing
with in this statement notice again how
she says None but the 144,000 can learn
that song for it is a song of their
experience
an experience such as no company have
ever had so are she is she talking about
uh other companies of redeemed people or
is she talking about other companies
what other companies wouldn't be able to
sing this song and this is where once
again we see this
statement there is a day just about to
burst upon us when God's Mysteries will
be seen and all his ways Vindicated when
Justice mercy and love will be
attributed to of his will be the
attributes of his throne when the
Earthly Warfare is accomplished and all
and the Saints all gather home our first
theme will be the song of
Moses all the
saints our first theme will be the song
of
Moses the second theme will be the song
of the Lamb the song of Grace and
Redemption this song will be Loft louder
loftier and in sublimer strains echoing
and re-echoing throughout the Heavenly
courts and then she says
this thus the song of God's Providence
is sung connecting the varying
dispensations remember how we talked
about
that there are like every generation
will have a part in this song yes I
remember that every dispensation there
are songs that people in the time of The
Exodus only they can sing right because
only they have it's their part right in
this song of the Lamb their Deliverance
this song it's their part of the song
right the people in the Reformation time
they have a they have a they've got a
part in the song the people at the end
of time they've got a part of the song
but all of them make up this song of
deliver who hasn't been delivered if if
it's a song of
Deliverance who in heaven is going to be
there that did not
did not experience Deliverance only the
angels and deliverance from the grave
Deliverance all of them experienc
deliverance from the grave right there
there are many who experience
deliverance from the grave and then
those who can't sing that song
deliverance from the grave because they
didn't
die that's that's a part they're not
going to be able to
sing
right those who went through the time of
trouble are cannot sing the song that
those sang in The Exodus or those sang
in the time of the Babylonian captivity
every one of God's people throughout all
dispensations have a part to sing in
that song I don't know I was just
thinking like God is so serious
about his laws and the way he governs
meaning like if if the Angels could sing
these songs they'd be bearing false
witness right because they didn't have
it's not a song of experience it's not
they haven't experienced it so they it
would be like yeah them singing God you
delivered me like exactly from what so
so andm let so M says what is the
difference then between those whose
names are written in the Book of Life
compared to those who areund no so
that's what I'm what I'm saying is there
is no difference it's the same
group right think of the 144,000 as
another name for the redeemed as another
name for the church right as another
name for uh the saved for as another
name for God's family as another name
for the the the promised Seed of Abraham
the Great multitude that Abraham was
it's the same group of people the
144,000 is simply a symbolic name
144,000 would be 12,000 time 12,000 why
the number 12 because 12 points to the
12 uh the 12 tribes of Israel of the Old
Testament 12 points to the 12 disciples
of the New Testament it is a combining
of all the Redeemed by the way the first
time the number 12 is used in the Bible
is used in connection with the word
service 12 is the symbol of
service therefore this is why the Bible
says these are they that serve him in
his Temple day and night right it is a
symbolic number for all the redeemed for
all who serve God in his Temple day and
night that's everybody that's all those
that have been saved okay let me go back
to the statement really quick I want to
say hi to ebony that's a high that was a
pine
for from freshman year so hi Ebony when
we were 14 years old I've known her
since amen wow so thank you for
worshiping with us today hello ebony
you've met ebony before I think I have I
think I have in Virginia yeah all right
so let's keep reading um the church
history upon the earth and the church
redeemed in heaven all center around the
cross of Calvary this is the theme this
is the song Christ All In All In anth of
Praise resounding from heaven from
thousand and 10,000 times 10,000 and an
innumerable company of the redeemed
hosts how many are singing a song
144,000 no thousands and 10 thousands
times 10,000s and a and an innumerable
company of the redeemed hosts sing the
song All unite in this song of Moses and
of the Lamb it is a new song for it has
never been sung before in
Heaven watch
this Holy
Angels will join in the song of the
redeemed though they cannot sing from
experimental knowledge he has washed Us
in his own blood and redeemed us unto
God yet they understand the great Peril
from which the people of God have been
saved were they not sent to lift up lift
up for them a standard against the enemy
they can fully sympathize with the
glowing Ecstasy of those who have been
overcome who have been over who have
been overcome by the blood of the lamb
and the word of their testimony so she's
clearly saying here that it is the
Angels the only the 144,000 can sing
this
song as compared to the angels who never
had that experience
right so when we go back to this idea of
only the 144,000 enter the temple I
would say it's the same thing right
here the angels for with this Temple
that is on Earth remember she talked
about they went up to heaven then they
came back down then they're going to the
temple and then Jesus raises his lovely
hand and say only the 144,000 enter here
I don't believe that's oh only this
group of people get to go in but that
group of people don't get to go in to me
it's
saying that this place is for humans
only and Angels can't even enter here
right that that special extra service is
just for human beings this is your place
because it is your experience right
right so and angels will be so happy for
us yeah that we get to sing that song
absolutely because they worked on our I
mean they did God's missions for us on
our behalf to save us to help to help in
situations you know what I'm saying so
right they're going to be really happy
that's right right sing that song that's
right um uh listen check this out we got
a few more slides and then we'll wrap it
up uh so let's go back to the screen
John while and vision saw a company
clothed with white robes an elder asked
him who they were and I said unto him
sir thou knowest not he said unto me
these are they or sir thou knowest and
he said unto me these are they which
came out of Great Tribulation and have
washed their robes and made them white
in the blood of the Lamb they were seen
in the temple of God this will be the
the result of all who lay hold on the
merits of Christ and wash their robes in
his
blood all who do this enter the temple
all who do this are seen in the temple
the temple is not set aside for some
group of people but not for others the
the temple is set aside for all the
redeemed right marching through and by
the way here's a statement where she
says uh marching through the marching we
all entered the cloud together and were
seven days ascending to the sea of glass
when Jesus brought the crowns of his own
right hand um and place upon Upon Our
Heads he gave us harps of gold I read
all this before but jump down to that
highlighted section she says Angels were
all about us as we marched over the sea
of glass uh to the gates of the
city the point I'm making here is that
through this whole Vision angels are
around them right so when she says Jesus
raised his lovely hand and said only the
144,000 enter this
place we have two options either some
people get to go in and others don't or
it is Humanity this place is is solely
for Humanity on Earth and a not even
angels get to enter this
place right so out of these two options
I'm going with it's the Angels just like
it was the angels can sing but they
can't really sing that song because it's
not their experience right that um
so let me do one more thing here I got
I'm going to do this as quickly as I can
okay
um Let me let me go to to to let me go
to the screen here and I want y'all to
notice
this we're talking about the
identification of the
144,000 the the rewards given to the
144,000 what we're about to see is that
they are scattered throughout the seven
churches
so for example
um in Revelation chapter uh uh in
Revelation chapter 3 where it talks
about Leo deia to him that
overcomes this is a promise that is
given the 144,000 overcame by the blood
of the
lamb in the fifth Church in the so we
know that the ceiling happens within the
context of the leodan church the end
time church but how about this
Revelation 3:12 Philadelphia the
Philadelphia Church to him that
overcometh will I make a pillar in the
temple of my God and he shall go out no
more and I will write upon him the name
of my God and the name of the city of my
God which is New Jerusalem so this is
this is part of the description of the
144,000 in the church period of
Philadelphia
MH so now you got the promises of to the
144,000 both in they they span
leoda and
Philadelphia all right how about
this
um the Church of Sardis th has a few
names even in Sardis which have not
defiled their garments they shall walk
with me in white for they are worthy let
me ask you are the 144,000 without
defilement do the 144,000 walk with God
because they did not defile their
garments yeah yet we find this attribute
in the Church of Sardis which is the
Church of the Reformation mhm um how
about how about this this is to the
pergamus church he that has an ear let
him hear what the spirit sayith unto the
church to the churches to him that
overcometh I will give to eat of the
Hidden mana and I will give him a white
stone and in the stone a new name
written which no man knoweth saving he
that receiveth it it is interesting that
Ellen White says in her uh 1846 Vision I
saw there tables of stone in which the
names of the 144,000 were engraved in
letters of gold the only place in the
Bible that even hints to people's names
being written in stone is in the Church
of pergamus where their names are
written in White in a in a
stone and what's interesting about this
is she doesn't say a table of stone as
if as in there was one huge table and
then you had the names of the 144,000
she says tables of stone how many tables
is that I don't
know
um there must be many tables right what
if we don't know but what if each table
has a name in it just one table per
Stone I mean one one name Stone per
Stone as Revelation he that overcometh I
will give it to him Stone we think of a
table as like a big thing but remember
in heaven right right our statures right
are greater than what they're going to
be here and so these names of these
Stones doesn't signify oh it's just 100
because everyone that is redeemed
receives a stone with their name in it
their new name in it so when we put all
of this
together oh by the way Smyrna do one
more here smna this is our last slide
fear none of those things which Thou
shalt suffer behold the devil shall cast
some of you into prison that you may be
tried and you shall have tribulation 10
days but be thou faithful unto death and
I will give thee a Crown of Life do the
144,000 receive a Crown of Life yes they
do the crown of life is received in
other words it's not just pergam it's
not just SM that receives the crown of
life every redeemed individual is gonna
receive a crown of life right it's not
just uh um
uh pergamus that I say it was that has
the white stone it's not just pergamus
that has the white stone every all the
redeemed from all the ages the rewards
given for each church are given to all
the
redeemed which is
another I think evidence proof that the
144,000 being the same has a great
multitude who wear crowns have a new
name have the father's name all of it
points
to this is one
group John hears the number
first and then he turns to look and he
sees what he just
heard he sees a great multitude he heard
he didn't see 144,000 he heard the
number MH and when he turns to look he
sees a great multitude that no man could
number right and this is the ultimate
fulfillment of the promise to
Abraham so Abraham has 12
children those 12 children grow into a
great
multitude I'm sorry not Abra Abraham has
Isaac who has Jacob but he is the father
of these 12 tribes right these 12
tribes prod they grew into a great
multitude so first it was just 12 mhm he
just had 12 sons oh man God's blessed
Abraham or God's blessed you know uh
Jacob with 12 sons
right but those 12 sons grew and
multiplied and multiplied and multiply
until at the end of the book you have a
great multitude
right that then is going to go through
persecution goes through that great
multitude that comes out of Egypt they
are one of the promise to
Abraham when Abraham gets to Heaven
God's not going to point to him point
out 144,000 people to him that was your
great promise that hey this your promise
but that great multitude yeah that's uh
that's another group of
no the
stars that cannot be numbered the dust
that cannot that's what God promised
Abraham the Sands and the Sea The Sands
of the sea so when Abraham gets to
Heaven this sand of the sea the stars of
the sky represents the 12 from the old
the 12 from the new the 12 under the old
Covenant the 12 under the New Covenant
12 uh 12 tribes 12 disciples it is a
symbolic number of the redeemed from
every age
God likes to do big
things out of something very little yeah
like Abraham had one son I mean y the
one that you're supposed to
have um and then you know from there was
able to build this great multitude yep
like there's just so much power in that
absolutely absolutely so this is our
closing slide this is a recap so who
understands the voice of God
all the
redeemed all everyone that is alive when
Jesus returns again and that's not just
144,000 people because there's a great
multitude that hear the truth and come
into present truth come into an
understanding of the truth right so all
that are alive hear the voice of God not
just
144,000 all are sealed not just 144,000
all form that perfect square not just
144,000 all stand on that sea of glass
not just 144,000 all sing the song not
just 144,000 from every age there were
those who were torn apart by death they
will all be reunited when Jesus comes
again not just 144,000 all have access
to the temple perhaps except the Angels
not just 144,000 people all have their
names written in stone not just 144,000
this to
me and let me say
this whether you believe the 144,000 is
literal or symbolic is not
salvational it's not
salvational there are people who say I
have evidence that it's literal and they
believe it and there's nothing you could
do to convince him and that and that's
fine it's not like your salvation is
based on what do you think is this
number literal or symbolic mhm
however and this is my only
warning if your belief leads you to
fear and leads you to act in ways that
are
contrary to the character of God because
now in trying to strive to be among that
special number that nobody else can be a
part of of you're now becoming
judgmental you're now becoming exclusive
you're now lifting your pride goes
Before Destruction so now you're like
man how can I be the best in my church
how can I beat out the others to claim a
spot among 144,000 now you're in trouble
right you say it's not
salvational and it's not unless it turns
into that but I I don't that's what I'm
saying yes yes I know but I don't see it
not turning into that I
it's very difficult not to turn into
that and I would take it this far to say
to believe that it's very difficult to
understand the true character I don't
believe that you can believe that and
really understand the true character of
God at the same time I know we like to
say two things can be true at the same
time not that one because now God is a
god of favorites right right so if God
is a god of favorites then it's probably
okay for me to act that way too right
right mhm
um and you know this is why it is so
important to
write apparently this is the most holy
person because they do X Y and Z and
look how they behave so I'm going to
behave that way too and then just most
people and this is what we need to
understand right the reason that the
devil messes with Doctrine is because it
Alters your picture of who God is yes if
God burns the wicked forever and he
enjoys it and he's like yeah cool is
that somebody you want to serve you're
have you're G to have a whole or have a
relationship with yeah you'll have a
whole group of of Christians in America
who cheer
on Mercy the cheer on in Glee and enjoy
watching other people suffer suffer like
because they don't believe like because
you don't believe like me well well then
God doesn't really like you God doesn't
really like you so I enjoy I'm going to
I'm going to gloat in you know whatever
I think is what God wants over what you
want mercy and so we see some of that
right now yeah when you when you have
this picture of
[Music]
God you begin to
excuse
Behavior not let me not say excuse you
begin to exhibit behavior that you think
is God like mhm the time is coming where
they that kill you they that persecute
you will think that they're doing God's
service but they're doing these things
because they have not known the father
that's what the text literally says
right they don't know me yeah and why do
they know him because what they've been
taught has skewed the picture of who God
is and that's all satan wants to do yeah
that's always been his main thing that
was his thing in heaven like no you guys
don't really know him mhm like I'm
closer to to him yeah I know him better
yeah and this is how he really is
yeah this is why it is so important I'm
going to still
say it's not salvational because there's
some people who are like yeah I think
the number is literal and I you know I'm
just going to strive to be in that
number and if I can't be in it then at
least I'm part of the Great multitude
and I'm good with that if you're not
judgmental you're kind and you see the
true character of God the right way okay
I'll accept that yeah but I don't know
to me those it is very very difficult
yeah I believe to hold that
belief and have that and if you have
that attitude praise God right but I can
tell you there are a lot of a lot of
people who don't have that attitude and
a lot of Ministries who who say listen
when you're teaching that everybody else
is in apostasy except for your ministry
except for your preaching you know and
you kind of go out on this yeah we're
the remnant within the remnant and we're
you know and you
start having that Spirit towards your
Breen uh that's where the trouble comes
in so uh this concludes our study for
the 144,000 on the 144,000 yeah it is
finally completed done it was very
crystal clear I'm glad that you we spent
the two first sessions going just Bible
and and then the last session kind of
dissecting Ellen White's writings on it
and I'm glad we spent that time yeah and
listen let me say people think that her
writings either contradict or they get
their whole belief system just life yeah
it it's kind of just like when we study
the Sabbath when we study any other
subject where is the where is the weight
of the evidence you got two positions
you ask yourself okay there's it seems
like there's evidence on this side and
it seems like there evidence on this
side but where is the weight of the
evidence wherever the weight of the EV
evidence is now your task is well how do
these these statements that may seem to
contradict the weight of the evidence
how would
I make these to to harmonize and if you
can find a way to harmonize them then
that is most likely the truth right you
never want to go for well there's less
evidence here so let me make the prop
the overwhelming amount of evidence
that's pointing this way let me try to
see if I can make that point this way to
where you know the Lesser position no
it's the other way around and when we go
to the Bible and we look at where the
evidence points then we go to the spirit
of Prophecy and we see oh it falls in
line with the Bible then we go what
about these statements oh okay well this
is why oh the Angels oh none can sing
the song This Is Why Oh yes there are
those who are going to be alive and
translated without seeing death but if
you look at the
144,000 as a title of the redeemed oh
that makes sense yes there are those
will be translated without seeing death
yes there were those there are those who
who died like sister Hastings but will
be part of the
144,000 and everything begins to to add
up and make sense yes okay it does amen
and you did pretty good you just went
over 15 minutes but you did good you did
good you did good we go yes thank you
for for being here and joining us for
this third and final study of the
144,000 uh it that's a blessing like I
said very crystal clear and uh we want
you to stay with us and continue to
worship with us into the Divine uh
Worship Hour and but we're just going to
close this off in prayer and then don't
miss reflections of Hope because uh Taj
apyp always has a blessing for us in
just like five minutes or so five
minutes gives us a huge blessing amen
let's pray heavenly father thank you
Lord for um uh helping us to complete
this study uh we know that it was a long
break in between Lord but um we'll put
this on a playlist Lord and pray and
pray for this will bless others who
watch it Lord um we ask that you would
help
us as we've been told to strive to be
among this group because it is striving
for salvation it's not just striving to
be part of a a a a special group no
we're told to strive because only those
in this group will be saved amen so Lord
help us to to be a part of this group
and we thank you Lord that this group is
a great multitude that no man could
number Lord I was studying the
remembering the other day that when the
Bible says there there is there will be
no more
sea over 70% of this earth is made up of
water and Lord I believe you you're
you're getting r r rid of this large
body of water because you have to make
space for the redeemed for the people
that will live on this planet Lord and
that ought to give us hope and
that yes while comparatively speaking
there will be more lost than are saved
yet still Lord the amount of people
saved
requires the removing of large bodies of
water to make space for those who have
accepted you as their lord and savior
amen so Lord please help us to be among
that group help us to have the Seal of
God the name of God written in our
foreheads your name your
territory Lord that's what we've always
set the seal has
been your your name your your your your
uh work your territory Lord write that
Upon Our Hearts Upon our minds and Lord
we thank you again for giving us that
hope thank you Lord redeem us is our
prayer in Jesus name amen amen amen
amen all right continue to worship with
us and we will see you in
church have you ever wanted something so
bad that you're willing to endure
intense suffering to obtain it willing
to sacrifice Comforts go through
hardships just to acquire it something
that was so attractive to you that you'd
be willing to do almost anything just to
see it well there's an Earthly place
that's kind of like that for
me 285 Mi off the coast of Mexico lies a
group of four volcanic islands that
shoot up from the Great Pacific Ocean
discovered in 1533 by Spanish explorers
the Riva hiiro Islands have been a top
destination for many more explorers
since then it is home to a handful of
naval officers who look after the
Mexican Naval Base on the island of
shakuro
it is also the center of the largest
Marine protected area in North America a
57,000 S M Marine Sanctuary a place of
Refuge for the creatures of the sea
where no fishing mining or tourist
development is allowed it is also a
UNESCO world heritage site that is
called by some as Mexico's little Hawaii
now it doesn't have the beautiful
beaches like we have back at home but it
does boast some of the most spectacular
pelagic diving in the world Lava Tubes
Rising like chimneys from the seaf Flor
provide the perfect backdrop for
plethora of pelic species to congregate
in peace there are schools of hammerhead
sharks seeking Rest by drifting in The
Ripping currents strong but yet peaceful
predators that are unbothered by our
presence you can hear humpback whales
sing their love songs while they nurse
their calves in the calm and clear
waters the friendly bottl dolphins are
intrigued by scuba divers and
consistently draw close for a playful
look the intelligence in their eyes and
their playful personalities testify to
the wisdom and joy of their makeup but
the main attraction of this incredible
place are the gigantic Oceanic mades
with wingspans of up to 20 ft wide these
gentle Giants seem to soar through the
ocean with Grace and Majesty their
behavior is almost inexplicable instead
of fleeing from us they constantly draw
near seeking for relax in massage in our
bubbles the eye to eye encounters with
these graceful creatures are a glimpse
of Heaven for
me to be in the presence of something so
large and yet So Graceful and peaceful
is all inspiring to say the least words
cannot describe the feelings of
exploring the Water World of the
Beautiful Creatures of sakor
and yet surprisingly there are only a
relative few were able to experience the
Splendor of this place why not more well
because sakuro is a very hard place to
get to unless you're one of the few
Mexican naval officers the only way to
get to these islands is by boat and
there's only a relative few boats that
bring only Advanced scuba divers only a
handful at a
time and due to the rough Seas there are
just a handful of months out of the year
where the waters are relatively calm
enough to set sail now once you do it's
a 24-hour boat ride to this isolated
place because of the long journey there
are no Daye trips one week is the
minimum amount of time you must be
willing to stay on the boat to
experience the Splendor of
[Music]
shakuro now for some people this may be
an easy Voyage to make but I on the
other hand suffer from a terrible
disadvantage despite my love for the
ocean I'm constantly plagued with
seasickness it is a curse for me there
are few things worse than being seasick
on a boat where there's no place to
escape for relief but despite this I'm
still willing to endure the 24-hour boat
ride and 7-Day journey to experience the
beauty and power of this place being
able to swim with the friendly Dolphins
the powerful sharks the singing whales
and the Majestic mantis make it more
than worth it to me
me our journey to sakuro reminds me of
another Journey that is also hard but
the destination is worth every step it
is the journey from Earth to heaven the
Bible says that is only through much
tribulation that we will enter into the
kingdom of God it tells us that the
afflictions of this world are what God
uses to prepare us for the eternal
Eternal wi of Glory to come and Jesus
said that only those who endure to the
end will be saved in order to make it to
the Heavenly sakuro we must be willing
to sacrifice Earthly Comforts and endure
the seasickness of trial and hardship
but when we get to the shores of Heaven
it will be worth it all the name sakuro
comes from the old English word sakur
which literally means to Aid and support
in times of hardship and distress these
isolated Islands
have truly been that for me a place of
relief from my seasickness and in a
similar way there is another place where
we can find relief from the seasickness
of sin and that my friends is at the
foot of the cross of Christ it is said
concerning Jesus for that he himself has
suffered being tempted he is able to
shakar to Aid to help to bring relief to
those who are also tempted you see Jesus
knows what it's like to experience the
Temptations that that we face in fact he
has already faced the pain and endured
the hardships that we've yet to
encounter for his desire to be with us
was so strong that he left the Comforts
of heaven and he set sail to the rugged
shores of our sinful World his yearning
for Eternal fellowship with us was so
great that he made the ultimate
sacrifice for us on the cross he took
our sin and our seasickness in order to
give us his soothing salvation and he
endured to the end when he said it is
finished and having been through all of
that he is now able to sucker us on our
way to the Heavenly sorum all we must do
is look to him for grace and strength so
remember that even though the journey
will be difficult and the sacrifices
will be great the destination will be
worth it all far better than the
Dolphins the Sharks the whales and the
Mantis to be with the maker of them all
in the unspoiled Paradise of God nothing
can compare and by God's suckering grace
I'll see you
[Music]
[Applause]
there we hope you've been blessed and
inspired by this new reflections of Hope
episode this episode is one of many
that's been produced all over the world
if you haven't done so yet please give
our video a like share it with your
friends and please follow us on
Instagram Facebook and YouTube if you'd
like to see more inspiring episodes and
get access to much more uplifting
content please go now to patreon.com
for/ revelation of Hope and sign up to
be a member of our patreon page your
monthly support will not only give you
early access to many more inspiring
videos but it will also enable us to
continue to produce more of these
cinematic object lessons from nature our
goal is to produce and release these
episodes much more frequently so please
prayerfully consider partnering with us
so that we may continue to share the
hope of Jesus all over the world thank
you so much for your support Aloha and
marinata
[Music]
welcome back living Mana church family
it's so good to have you continue to
still be here with us us and if you have
just joined us right now for the church
service welcome to living Mana church
and please put in the chat if you're
just joining us now for the first time
today please put in the chat where you
are worshiping from we like to get to
see where you're worshiping from and to
get to know you a little bit and say
welcome to you so we are just thankful
to all of you that are here and if this
is your first time please put a one in
the chat so we can say a special
welcome to you it is such a blessing to
be back here with all of you we missed
you last week but like I said in our uh
previous program that even when we're
gone we try to tune in uh and see what's
happening here at Living Mana church so
technically we're still with you we're
just not here in the studio with you but
we are just always thrilled to to return
back and to be worshiping with you live
uh here at Living Mana church so want to
say welcome to Jerry from San Diego
Jerry it's always good to see you from
beautiful San Diego uh California
welcome uh here which is your living
Mana Church good to see you here and uh
just again put a one in the chat if this
is your very first time because we want
to just let to let you know a little bit
about living Mana church and guys we are
excited about what God is doing here
with living man and church and we're
very excited to get to meet many of you
at the convocation you're going to get
more information about that here very
shortly um and it's just exciting
because we're you know this year flew by
like we're already uh heavy into
December and before you know it it will
be 2025 and guys on April 9th it will be
living manate Church's third birthday
and it's our anniversary it's going to
be our anniversary and I just wow um it
just amazes me of what God has done with
this church in three short years but I
just want to also welcome Wendy from
Idaho and Annette from Kansas welcome uh
to living Mana church we have sister
Joanne from trinad and Tobago such a
blessing sister Joanne that that that
what you do here at Living manage church
and being on the prayer team and helping
with the lmlc kids we thank you for that
uh sister uh Valerie as well happy
Sabbath good to see you and so thankful
uh to all of you that are here and that
are worshiping with us today here at
Living manage church just want to let
you guys know how you can stay connected
to living Mana church it's so very
important because we're online 100% so
we don't you're not you know you don't
get to run into each other at church or
you know get a bulletin with
announcements or things like that so
you're going to get all your information
and all your announcements in two ways
and one of those ways is that you can
sign up to get text and you can do that
uh by sending LM o to
8552741386 church so there's people who
are all over the world and we praise God
for that so the way that you can get
your information which is is you want to
go to Mighty networks you want to sign
up for Mighty networks and that is our
virtual Church home that is our Church
Without Walls that is where you're going
to get all the information about what uh
living Mana church is doing and um
you'll be able to get notifications when
we're going live and what programming is
coming up all of those things you can do
that there you can find out about small
all the small groups that we have you
can find out there when they're meeting
who's leading you can message the leader
you can get a ton of information you can
also make friendships there on Mighty
networks and that is where Community can
be formed as well um because you're
interacting with the other members or
viewing audience from all around the
world so you want to sign up for Mighty
networks and if you are watching on the
living Mana YouTube channel you U that
link has been put um in the chat so
please follow that um so that you can
sign up for Mighty networks and so
that's like a huge way that you can stay
connected and get information about
living Mana church so I want you guys
also to know about amosi kids we have an
amazing program for kids
and we are just so excited about that so
you can bring your children uh to LML
kids on Sabbath morning and it starts at
11:30 central time you can get and
that's on alter live um but you can get
more information by texting kids to that
855 number or you can send an email um
to that email that you see there on your
screen and the leadership of LMO C kids
will re they will reach out to you so
you can get your kids involved and
signed up and we have an amazing
leadership team that has been vetted to
work uh with our children and so you can
also know it's a very safe space to
bring uh your children each and every
Sabbath also just want to let you guys
know about membership we get that get
those questions all the time like how
can I become a member of the church and
so if you are already a Seventh Day
Adventist member and are part of the
church you can
um request to transfer your membership
and you can send an email to Patrice and
you can you know contact your local
church where your membership is and all
of that process will get started for you
if you are of have already been baptized
and you are just learning about the
Seventh Day Adventist Church and you are
liking what you hear and you want to
join you can come in on profession of
faith and you can become a member of
living Mana church that way and if you
would like to get baptized you can also
uh do studies with Pastor Meyers um and
our Bible work team and you will be able
to be baptized and to come in that way
so there's three different ways that you
can become a member of the living Mana
Church also want you guys to know that
Pastor Myers does have Virtual Office
hours so if you would like to connect
with him you can also send an email to
Patrice at Living mana. live and she
will get that set up and organized for
you you know here at Living Mana church
we have a prayer team and like I I
explained to people when I when I meet
them and talk to them and describing
what living Mana church is all about and
when I say that the that the our prayer
team I'm like you guys this is not just
any old prayer team I just have to I
just have to try to explain I was like
they're kind of a church within the
church they are a part of living manage
church but it's such a massive thing
that they do because of all the prayer
requests that come in and all the
community that is formed and the
connections like people really they they
the prayer team attracts people to
living Mana church I think that's one of
our our big gifts here at Living Mana
church is that people are like you know
what that church really prays and when I
send my text or if I put it in the chat
then I heard brother Terry praying over
me there live and if he can't get to it
our prayer team is praying over those
prayer requests so if you would like
your prayer request re EST to be prayed
over you can email pray Living mana.
Church you can also go to Mighty
networks and there's a prayer wall you
can put the request there or you can
text pray to that 8552741386
Mana Church YouTube page and click
subscribe um and to get notifications
click like all of those things uh we
would like for you to do because we are
uh growing the living Mana YouTube page
um as well and so please go over and do
that we would be so thankful for you to
you for doing that you know here at
Living Mana church we are all getting to
know each other and one of those ways is
is to know about when your birthday is
you know some people they just are like
oh I don't you know my birthday is not a
big deal I don't know about you but for
me I love my birthday and I love to
celebrate it every year uh in different
ways and so we would like to at least
just be able to wish you guys a happy
birthday so um that list is being
compiled so please um if you would like
to send uh just send your name and birth
date to that email there that's on the
screen because we would like to just
celebrate with you on your special
day now for the exciting news about the
convocation oh man you guys heard some
during Sabbath school so I can tell you
there's some really really amazing fun
things that are being planned for the
convocation so you're going to be
spiritually fed of course you're going
to be spiritually fed this is living
Mana church right so it's going to be
you're going to get a spiritual blessing
you're going to have great fellowship
and you're going to have a lot of fun
while you're doing it so guys if you are
on the fence and you have not decided
I'm trying to kindly push you over the
fence to say and then pray about it pray
about it if God can put it together so
you can make it because it's going to be
a great experience as you see our theme
is bread of life and so we want you to
be there May 1 to the 4th in Orlando
there are some fun things and I'll give
you more detail about some of those
things um and and the weeks coming up
but
please um scan this QR code and I'm
giving you time as I'm talking please
grab your phones those of you who know
how to do that scan the QR code there's
also if you're watching on the living
Mana um YouTube there is a link in the
chat there's a link in the chat so click
on that that is where you can register
and also um it's going to take you to
where you can uh do your uh registration
for your for your rooms as well so the
link in the chat is there and you can
also just scan it so again for those of
you who are not familiar with how to
scan a QR code just put your phone like
you're taking a picture so you want to
open up your picture app on your phone
where it says phone and you want to
point your phone directly to that QR
code if you're watching on a computer
screen or if you're watching it um on
your TV you can just put that that scan
it with the the picture app um on your
phone and just push the button like
you're going to take a picture and that
will take you to uh the link where you
uh can register so we're so excited to
have all of this um planning that we're
doing so that we can all just really
enjoy the fellowship there and so again
the link is in the chat so you can do
that or you can scan the QR code but
definitely want you guys to be there and
just uh to be able ble to be part of the
fellowship it's going to truly be a
blessing and so I want to tell you guys
also about a program for our youth
Friday Night Lights this is ages 13 to
18 7M Central you can get more
information by uh emailing lmos kids
that you see there on your screen um and
so it's an amazing youth plan to run the
whole thing themselves so they are
running uh this service and it's called
Friday night light so if you have a
young person that's between the ages of
13 and 18 please make sure that they uh
will be there so they can
experience um the blessing the blessing
of being a part of Friday night light I
also want to tell you about um the
testimony Thursdays with Lami Richard
and that's um so mark your calendars for
December 19th at 700 p.m. central Time
he has something special coming your way
um and so it's going to truly be a
blessing this is the pilot episode
episode excuse me and will feature an
amazing testimony by uh
wifredo uh wifredo from wifredo music
and you don't want to miss this
inspiring and uplifting story I
personally have not heard this story but
I know that if LAN mmy feels like this
is his first episode and he wants to
really bring us a blessing I know that
this is going to be a blessing so make
sure you mark your calendars uh for that
event and so we're just so excited to be
a church that is able to have
programming happening um just all days
of the week all days of the week and so
we have Monday Tuesday Wednesdays and
Thursday Fridays if we even have Fridays
because you do have we have uh the gyms
do uh their uh adult Sabbath school
lesson on Friday evenings and even the
Friday Night Lights so I think only
Sunday might be the only day we don't
have something going on here at Living
Mana church but it truly is a blessing
want to just remind you all about living
Mana Global this is truly a blessing uh
we have seven different languages that
um that our messages here are being
translated
um in that's Ukrainian Korean Arabic
Hindi Chinese Japanese and Spanish and
so for those of you who are not familiar
and we're going to you know do something
on our Sabbath school so that you guys
can just learn more about exactly uh
what it is and what it looks like but
there is technology that uh makes it
look like that Pastor Myers is speaking
Ukrainian in the messages that he's
preaching or Korean or Chinese or Hindi
or all those seven languages I just
mentioned and so the editors take his
sermon that he does for us here in
English and they translate um the slides
and the system automatically translates
the language but then we have to take it
through review to people who actually
speak that language um and understand
the message in English to make sure that
it's matching so it's a whole process
that has to be uh done but um just it's
so it's it's a lot of work but it's a
blessing so if you have and we already
have some of the messages up on LM
Global so please look for that and if
you know anyone who speaks the languages
the seven languages that I just
mentioned Ukrainian Korean Arabic Hindi
Chinese Japanese or Spanish then please
direct them uh to uh Elmos or living
Mana Global I should say sorry to living
Mana Global so they can see uh these
messages in their language and um we're
definitely highlighting the Evangelistic
messages uh cuz has a whole playlist of
evangelism on uh the Youtube channel and
so we are highlighting those first and
we're editing those first so please
direct them uh to living Mana Global and
they can hear it again in their language
and just remember living manag Global uh
when you are thinking and praying about
giving and supporting um living Mana
church we thank you so much for that
speaking of that just want to remind you
how how you can continue to give and
bless living man at church and if you if
you're already giving thank you for the
blessing and allowing God to use you in
the way that he is using you um but the
way right now where you can give
virtually is by going to
adventistgiving.org that's
adventistgiving.org you put in living
Mana church and you will see a tithe
envelope uh if you click to the right
hand you will see a tithe envelope and
you can see there on your screen there's
a place where you can put um how much
tithe you are giving how much you're
giving an offering to the local church
uh budget and then there's other there
other line items that you will see there
you will see a benevolence fund you will
um see many other things there um that
you can be able to give to and our
benevolence fund is where we are able to
help others who contact the church and
are in need um of some assistance so
we're able to do that through that fund
so just as you are praying about your
giving um just remember to to to look at
that tithe envelope where you will see
other items where you can give as well
if you are needing to mail in um your
tithe and offering you can do that by
mailing it to PO Box 428 Owens
Crossroads Alabama
35763 just send a little note to let us
know where you would like your funds to
to go if it's for tithe or offering or
both or for benevolence fund or wherever
you would like to see it to go and we
will make sure that it makes it to that
right area and part of the ministry of
living Mana church so again we are just
so thankful and so blessed by God and by
God using you and you being faithful to
God um in answering um his call um to to
give and to support living Mana church
again living Mana church will be 3 years
old in April and it's a miracle and it's
a blessing from God all that he uses
this church to do and we're already
starting to plan for 2025 like it's
going to be a new year so we want to
continue to get better we don't want to
stay the same we want to we want to grow
with God as he grows as he pushes on us
to grow more we want to grow more and so
we want to go into all the world in even
new ways and just be better at what we
do and so God is um he's he's a unique
God and so he's just always calling us
to just go higher and higher and higher
and that's our goal for living Mana
church so that we can reach as many
people as we can giving this gospel
message it's because of you and your
faithfulness and what you do for living
Mana church that we're able to do these
things and we just say thank you we are
so blessed Again by God and by your
faithfulness so if you would just bow
your heads with me as we pray a prayer
of Thanksgiving just praising God for
all that he does for for this church and
for each and every one of you us all of
us bow your heads with me as we
pray Heavenly Father Lord I Thank you
for this sabbath Lord I Thank you for
all your Miracles that you are working
and I know like in my life personally
and my family's life Lord you've been
working in my brother's situation you've
been working in uh Pastor Myers's
brother situation and as a family we
thank you we we thank you for all that
you're doing Lord I Thank you for this
amazing church this loving Church
everyone who makes up this church is a
blessing uh to us and to others in this
church Lord and I just pray for them um
everyone who supports and comes and
attends this church Lord I pray for them
we all are going through something we're
never just free of not uh being targeted
in different ways by the enemy and so
Lord I just lift up every family that is
facing um a trial or issues going on in
the home Lord I pray for them I pray for
every marriage for the children Lord I
pray for those who are dealing with
health issues we know it so well and
personal for our own family Lord and so
I just pray that you will strengthen and
encourage them those who are
individually going through the health
journey and those who are just family
trying to support that person Lord
strengthen all of them help them to just
believe in you and to have that faith
and that peace knowing like my shirt
says it's not going to be easy but Faith
makes it possible for us to believe and
it allows us to have hope that you are
doing something in the
situation so Lord I I lift up um our Our
World Church this conference Lord that
the leadership will um just continue to
um just be able to organize so that all
of these our churches and the pastors
will we just all go into all the world
Lord and to minister and to all of the
areas that you have given us to minister
here for living Mana church it's the
whole world for other churches and
pastors it is that local area so I just
pray a blessing over them um as they are
doing their Ministries as well Lord we
just want to we we see how messed up
this world is and how much they need you
Lord I pray for the family of the two
young boys the five and the six-year-old
that were shot this week at the 7day
Adventist School in California I pray
for those families Lord I it's a miracle
that these little boys are alive and so
we thank you for saving their life and
Lord I know the healing Journey for them
is going to be massive and so we just
pray that you will strengthen the family
strengthen the the young boys the little
boys um as they will have to deal with
the healing and the injuries that have
happened to them Lord and so I know that
whole Community has been traumatized and
so I just pray for that Community as
well and Lord really these type of
situations just want make us want to go
to heaven and just remind us that this
is not our home and we should not get
comfortable here because this is the way
the world is is not where we that's not
where God wants us to stay or to be and
so Lord help us to continue to connect
to you and have a relationship with you
and grow in your love every day Lord so
that you are preparing us to leave this
place Lord and help us to to be a
blessing to others which you have called
us to be and to do and to share this
message with others Lord I pray for
pastor Meyers and the message I just
pray that the holy spirit will use him
today to touch our hearts in a very
special way and I ask all of these
things in Jesus name
amen thank God can't use
you think he only uses perfectly
qualified
people take a closer
[Music]
look Moses was not a great
speaker Jonah ran from
God Jacob was a
liar Noah got drunk
Rahab was a
prostitute David had an
affair Jeremiah was depressed a
lot Solomon was rich in wisdom but poor
in lifestyle John the Baptist was just
plain
poor Timothy was too young Abraham was
too old Lazarus was
dead Sarah was Barren Naomi was a widow
Gideon and Thomas both doubted and so
did Sarah Peter lacked
[Music]
self-control James and John were
self-righteous Paul had a short fuse
well so did Peter and Moses actually
lots of people
did God's Army isn't perfect it never
has been it's the march of the
unqualified get in line
[Music]
Mary Mary did you
know that your baby boy would someday
walk on a
water Mary did you know that your baby
boy would save our sons and
daughters did you know
that your baby boy has come to make you
new the child that you've
[Music]
delivered will soon
deliv you Mary did you
know that your baby boy would give sight
to a blind man Mary Did You know that
your baby boy would come to storm with
his hands did you
know that your baby boy has walked Where
Angels
TR when you kiss your little
baby then you've kissed the face of God
Mary did your know
no the blind will see the death will
hear the dead will live
again the lame will leap the dumb will
speak the Praises of the Lamb
oh Mary did you
[Music]
know that you're bab boy is the Lord of
All
[Music]
Creations Mary did you
know that your baby boy would one day
rule the
nation did you
know that your baby born
is Heaven's perfect
lamb the
sleeping child you're
holding is the
great The
Great I
Am
oh Mary Mary Mary Mary Mary
did you
[Music]
know here at Living Mana we bear each
other's burdens when you need support or
prayer when you're feeling
discouraged or alone or
anxious you don't have to face life
struggles alone
[Music]
let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain obain mercy and
find Grace to help in our time of
need the Lord is close to the
Brokenhearted and saves those who are
crushed in spirit
[Music]
amen there we go amen praise God praise
God blessings and happy Sabbath living
Mana Church hey there we go welcome
Saints happy Sab Sabbath to you all
wherever you are are uh coming in from
we just welcome you here today we love
you we love to pray with you and for you
and uh let's just continue to uh be
obedient in this service and uh and be
about God's businesses as we pray what a
what a wonderful wonderful privilege it
is amen amen wait a that song right
before this little wow that little young
lady is just beautiful awesome that
truly bless
yeah absolutely you know I just want to
encourage everybody online um whatever
platform you you're on please uh
continue to put your prayer requests uh
to place them in the chat we have prayer
warriors that are collecting those
prayers and we are literally praying
over those prayers all week long amen
amen and you know I like the I I um I
also want to just REM mention to a
little bit we do have our special ops
groups prayer groups and those are very
focused prayer groups and I'm going to
tell you God has done some miraculous
things through those prayer groups amen
hasn't he and you know we're learning
God has taken us to higher Heights and
deeper deps in him you know he's really
challenging our faith he's challenging
us to deny self more he's he's revealing
to us that or he's calling to us he's
calling us to a higher standard a higher
standard of Faith a higher standard of
prayer and fasting and a higher and a
higher level of denying self would you
say amen amen and and amen and just the
things you know it's it's so phenomenal
that you know when you pray for others
you realize the Revelation is while you
praying for others God is working things
out in you amen your character that
refinement that growing and I I I just
want to also hit hint upon this
or we don't just pray for people I think
that is one of the important that is one
of the most pivotal things I think I
have learned from our Focus prayer
because I'm a part my husband and I are
part of one of the uh special office
teams and we found that we're not just
praying for people we're praying with
them we're walking side by side with
them on their Journey we're actually in
the trenches in this Warfare with them
right when they cry we cry when they
when they're joyous we're joyous and my
goodness what a work God is doing in
that you know holding up the Blood
Stained Banner you know and and a and as
a group it is just it is just wonderful
and I would encourage everyone if you
feel a call if you feel God has called
upon you and had placed in
you the spirit of intercessory prayer
reach out to our prayer group brother
Terry and and you know let him know that
you're interested in participating in
one of on one of our special ops teams
amen amen amen amen blessings yeah we
just uh Power of prayer it changes
things it does prayer changes wi and I
experience it yeah and we'll continue to
stand on the on the intercessory prayer
with all that we have amen and I just
want to give a a praise before we get
started and just mentioned we're filling
in for for our normal brothers and
sisters our prayer lead
uh uh brother Terry and sister amra
they're not here today uh thank God they
are home safe and resting and and God is
uh blessing them and they're healing
them and we just thank God for how he
moves swiftly in and is covering them so
keep them in your prayers Lord we
continue to pray for them uh in the name
of Jesus Lord we thank you for them uh
amen they've been a great tribute to to
uh to me and my wife and this team and
what they're doing here at Living manate
Church yes yes we are thankful for their
leadership and we're and they lead not
just by they lead not just by words or
guidance but by example and I think that
is just such a blessing you know to lead
by example because a lot you say so much
more about how you walk than what you
can say and praise God Amen I'm I'm
chuckling because of something I just
saw in the chat sister TR say for a
minute there our brother came on and I
had to do a double take cuz I thought I
was looking at Danny lob oh but that
isn't that a common thing I get that a
lot
am poor
guy anyway amen well let's go to this is
the time of Praise You know we would not
even ask anything of God before we first
open our mouths to praise God for what
he has done he has done great and mighty
things this week I have a list of Praise
reports here amen and do you know God
inhabits the Praises of his people
and Saints I just want to encourage you
when you're going through when you feel
like you don't know what to say praise
praise God for what he's done praise God
for his goodness Praise Him for Life
Praise Him for strength he inhabits the
Praises of his people amen praise
through that circumstance and that
situation you're going through you know
God is is is he wants he's raising us up
to be a people of praise to praise him
through the storm because as we're as
Praises go forth there a song that comes
down blessings come down right amen and
those blessings are my faith I'm
encouraged I I I'm giving the the
strength to endure those Praises give us
strength to endure amen amen and I'm
going to Pro uh uh give you I'm just
going to go through some of our Praises
we've gotten this week and praise God
for these from our very own sister
Valerie she says hi guys just a little
update I had an eye appointment
yesterday and the doctor told me to get
some eye drops for my eye for my dry
eyes I went to Walmart to get them and
decided to get some fruit and non-dairy
yogurt and allergy pills I was expecting
to use a riding cart because I woke up
hurting well there wasn't any available
so I parked my Walker and pushed a
shopping cart for 45 minutes pushed a
shopping cart for 45 minutes I was not
happy at first but then I thank the Lord
for the strength he gave me to do it
hallelujah praise God she wasn't happy
about it at first but then she praised
God for the strength Praise Him in the
storms and and you know she did that for
45 minutes and that was not a small feed
brothers and sisters praise God and then
God revealed to her praise me for the
strength I'm giving you the strength to
do this you know and and that's how God
revealed who he is there's a saying that
says man's extreme ities to only bring
about God's opportunities to work in our
lives amen sister G last Sabbath I was
extremely ill my body had two different
bacterial infections I had several
wounds that wouldn't healed and my body
could no longer heal itself I was going
to wait until Monday to go to the doctor
but by God's grace got an appointment on
Friday afternoon but by Friday morning I
was so overcome my body just gave out on
me the left side of my body was super
hot to to the touch I had a dangerously
high fever if I had waited 48 Hours more
it would have turned septic and because
it was only on my left side would have
hit my heart within two
weeks but God I love that but God as
soon as the word got out that I was sick
people stopped dropped and prayed the
graphics team the prayer team and many
church members began to pray well I
should
say went Next Level went to the next
level with their prayers because they're
always praying for me and others exactly
one week later I am doing so much better
I have definitely turned the corner and
all my wounds are completely healed
hallelujah hallelujah except the worst
one but it's much better in healing I am
allergic to most antibiotics and highly
resistant to many so my treatment
options are very few the first
medication has been working well and I
ask people to pray I would have any side
effects and I haven't had any when I
think how sick I I was a week ago to
where I am today only God the Almighty I
am the god that Health thee of all our
diseases hallelujah amen please be
encouraged because God hears our prayers
and answers out of his great love and
mercy don't ever give up because God can
do a lot in seven days I humbly ask to
please continue to pray that God will
make a way for me to get a certain
medications that needed I praise God for
always giving us what we need right away
when we need it keep trusting keep
believing keep playing praying thank you
to everyone who keeps us covered in
prayer thank you for those who hold up
the arms that keep us covered in prayer
thank you for my church to my church
family amen amen hallelujah and then we
have isn't that a beautiful praise
Hallelujah and then we have a praise
report from our own dear sister
Charlotte praise God I'm scheduled for
discharge home Monday doctor says I have
about a year of recovery and Rehab when
I get home I hope to be able to resume
whatever I can do for our friends in
Pakistan God bless God bless amen yes
praise God God is good God is good to us
all and in every situation or
circumstance we can always find
something to be grateful for to praise
God for in that right amen amen amen I
love those Praises when people testify
and your testim monies are just
powerful the those that are going
through and thinking that God is not
listening he is and he is still on the
throne he's still healing he's still
delivering and he's still answering
prayers so I just I just want to
encourage you don't give up don't give
up God is working behind the scenes and
working on your behalf and and just
Delights in delivering you and healing
you so hang in there brothers and
sisters and as we uh join our faith
together let's go handle God business of
prayer today yes and um just be mindful
of those that uh that we're praying for
join Faith with us as we lift him up
before the throne of grace and believe
and receive that God will hear and
answer your prayers amen amen so let us
pray Father in heaven we come to you
today humbly and boldly Lord we just
come uh standing on your word your
promises Lord first of all let me just
say thank you for all those blessings
and miracles father that you have have
blessed your people with a healing
father that you have done in the lives
of these people Lord in Jesus name thank
you for GG's praise Lord thank you for
sister amma's praise thank you for
sister B's praise and all those Praises
Lord that just went up father you are
still God and you are still Mighty and
you can do all things and all things are
possible Lord to those that believe and
we just lift this up to you today Father
We join our faith together today Lord as
we pray Lord on one Accord believing and
receiving Lord and asking your divine
intervention your healing power Lord to
be upon these prayers today as we lift
them up to you today Father with
expectations and Hope and Faith father
in Jesus name father I just pray and
lift these names up to you T now as we
intercede father once again I just want
to lift up uh sister ammer Lord continue
your healing upon her father thank you
for watching over her Lord and continue
that healing process thank you Lord for
moving in swiftly Lord and doing what
Only You Can Do Lord and I Just Praise
You Lord be with them both Lord thank
you for brother Terry for being by his
uh wife side Lord and keeping her uh
strong and and doing that manly Duty
Lord in Jesus name thank you for these
leaders Lord and what they're doing in
our church Lord continue to strengthen
them and guide them in the precious name
of Jesus Lord father I lift up uh Wendy
Allen Lord by praying that her niece
will get victory over alcohol in the
precious name of Jesus Lord oh God touch
her Lord and father pull her in close
Lord we pray against this addiction of
alcohol father pray that you can save
her and minister to her Lord before
alcohol takes over father and we just uh
trust in you and Believe In You Lord
that her family is surrounded by her
Lord speaking words of wisdom father we
pray that you will pierce her heart Lord
and open her eyes and her ears Lord that
she can hear a word from you and
manifest yourself into her life Lord you
don't like one uh uh to perish Lord and
we don't want to either father alcohol
is a is a can have its stronghold on her
life Lord and we just break that
stronghold in the name of Jesus Lord and
deliver her father in Jesus precious
name I pray amen
amen
Adriana uh has a private request and
also praying for challenges and family
salvation father we just pray for her
whatever it is in her heart Lord and the
challenges that she's facing Lord we
pray that you intervene in her life Lord
and give her uh give her that ability
Lord to just listen and be still and be
patient Lord while you work on her her
behalf Lord and not be uh uh Swift and
and and and quickly to to take things in
her own hands Lord but just be still and
patient and wait upon you Lord and have
you minister to her Lord where you can
pour into her Lord that she can give her
the ears to hear Lord the eyes to see
where you're working on her behalf
father God and father I pray for her
salvation Lord in Jesus name Lord we
lift her up to you now Lord cover her
Lord protect her Lord in the G in Jesus
name I pray amen
uh Lila
Peterson is praying oh praying for the
people that were in the hurricane Helen
in North Carolina amen amen thank you
Father for that request Lord we pray for
those families those people that that
need your help Lord and help them
recover Lord we pray that there was no
fatality I don't know the news didn't
hear about it but father we just pray
for this family Lord that you will
restore and recover and and uh and and
and just watch over lord we uh just
plead the blood of Jesus over them right
now father I don't know the damage but
father I know that you can restore I
know that you can deliver and I know
that you will watch over them in the
precious blood of Jesus I pray amen
amen and
Rebecca I think I'm saying the name
right yeah
right thanking God for the knee surgery
and still praying for an appointment
apartment amen father thank you for the
healing of the knee continue to work on
their behalf Lord strengthen their knee
and the ligaments Lord and and just
strengthen where they can be able to
walk comfortably Lord and as they give
you praise Lord continue Lord to to
allow them to walk and and just move
without restriction and pain and uh
thank you for those that are around them
Lord and keep them garded up and and
eyes focused upon you father God and and
I pray that you will provide for their
every need father they're asking looking
and praying for an apartment to open up
father you're a great provider Lord and
we know that you will open that door in
the precious name of Jesus Lord thank
you for hearing and answering that
prayer Lord in Jesus precious name we
pray amen bless God uh Candace bu uh
praying for living situation while we
lift up her situation to you right now
father we know that sometime we to worry
about where you doors will open up
father where you can find a home and a
place of rest but father you have never
failed father we're asking you to
intervene father provide a place father
living circumstances that you open the
door Lord that she can walk you Lord
somebody will give her a place to and we
just claim that victory in the name of
Jesus Christ amen amen thank you Jesus
thank you God Kila please pray for my
mom Salma and and for her College exams
and uh traveling grace this weekend amen
father we lift up her mom Salma to you
father we pray that you will continue to
watch over heal and protect and provide
for her every need father strengthen her
father in the precious name of Jesus
father we pray for her Lord as she her
mind is focused on in spite of all she's
doing Lord she's studying in school for
exams Lord and we pray that you'll calm
all fears and soothe all nerves Lord and
just be with her Lord and and uh help
her uh uh pass this exam and clear her
mind father that we should just whiz
through this thing Lord and and keep all
the other things off her mind Lord and
stay focus on an on point of what she is
trying to accomplish Lord cover her Lord
cover me be with her Lord in the
precious name of Jesus Lord we pray
traveling grace be with her Lord as
travel this weekend in Jesus name amen
and Lord I pray for Lana lvania Miller
is praying for healing and father once
again father we just ask you to continue
Lord to give uh your healing power Lord
to those that are praying for it Lord
they have the power youve given us the
authority to claim and speak over
circumstances Lord we pray in the name
of Jesus father for healing Lord uh we
speak healing over her Lord wherever she
stand in need of Father she can claim it
and embrace it in the name of Jesus Lord
cover her bless her Lord Heal her Lord
wherever she's hurting father in the
precious name of Jesus I pray amen amen
and at Faith uh I believe it's Faith uh
pray for my private request for healing
father we just again Lord we lift up a
healing request to you now father you
know what they stand in need of Lord and
and just touch their body Lord and uh as
they call upon your name father you
you're a God that's nothing's too hard
for you and father not how they
surrender their heart to you lord
they're asking for healing and father
you will deliver Lord you hear their cry
you will deliver heal them in the
precious name of Jesus I pray amen amen
amen praise God Mr sneak sneak say pray
for me and my wife and we have
a we have a virus Lord and we just they
both are sick so we pray for this family
Lord we pray for them right now in the
name of Jesus we know how viruses can
take take hold and do but father we
claim it blood over it right now and
stop it in its tracks Lord and and turn
it around and rid their body of it Lord
and give them strength Lord build up
every cell in their body Lord that they
can fight and resist this virus in the
name of Jesus Lord be with their doctors
Lord in Jesus name father I think I
believe that they're healing but father
give them even more healing power just
cover them Lord and restore them Lord
and deliver them Lord in the precious
name of Jesus I pray amen
amen um Jennifer Robinson is praying for
sister Brenda that uh that both are sick
Lord and we lift them up to you as well
father we continue to pray father for
this uh that we have you've given us the
power Lord we will win this battle
against sickness and disease father
because you give us the word to speak
over so Lord we speak healing over these
this family right now father that you
will touch them we ask him for Divine
Healing father wherever they stand in
need of Father heal and touch father and
restore in Jesus precious Name Lord and
and and speak to their hearts as well
father and they give you praise and
honor and glory Lord and just continue
to walk with them and strengthen them
Lord going and coming Lord and uh we
just Praise Your Name Lord for the
healing father that they're about to
receive in Jesus name amen amen praying
for a speedy recover form as
well Daniel Castillo and his father and
brother Lord father we just pray for
this family Lord their men and father
and son and brother the men of the
family Lord we just pray that you will
minister to them and draw them close
Lord and uh uh speak uh blessings over
them Father that whatever it is whatever
the struggles may be Lord we pray for
your divine intervention Lord to calm
the storms and and and and and and
reveal love and and and and just Bond
them together father that they can know
where the love and help comes from
father and turn that situation around
and let them see love Through The Eyes
Of God lord and praying for salvation
and whatever it is that enemy stronghold
the enemy has we denounce it in the name
of Jesus Lord and bond them together
Lord and and not let uh a wedge be
driven between this family Lord we just
pray that you draw them close and
minister to them and bless them Father
in the precious name of Jesus I pray
amen uh Estella white praying for family
spiritual strength amen amen father
thank you for that request Lord thank
you for this person someone to ask for
spiritual health and strength lord
they're fighting they're coming to you
they're seeking you the only help they
know where their help comes from father
they're praying for SP spiritual
strength father God so we pray that you
anoint them and strengthen them Father
fill them with your Holy Ghost Lord give
them the power Lord to speak over their
circumstances father and and claim
victory Lord in the name of Jesus father
continue to walk with them and
strengthen them Lord in Jesus precious
name I pray amen amen and we continue to
pray for our dear brother Trevor Lord we
just cover him and bless him Lord we
continue to lift him up before you Lord
and uh help him uh gain control Lord and
and be strengthen Lord and denounce the
lies that the enemy has telling him
father we love him and we know you love
him more Lord we just cover him in the
pl blood of Jesus Lord and uh give you
all the praise for how you have watched
him and how you have brought him to but
Lord continue to to uh bless this
brother strengthen him Lord in every
area he stands in need of I just ask all
these things in Jesus name I pray amen
amen and we proceed on in prayer we
lifting up S bers online which is the
name of the
and he's asking for prayer he says my
income has been maliciously attacked and
lessened pray for God Direction strength
and ability to manifest and receive the
manner God has for him he's able praise
God absolutely brother uh uh absolutely
because even though that prayer it was
asked in faith and strength you've
already claimed the promises of God he
will give you Direction strength and
ability he will manifest his glory and
all will turn out uh that which the
enemy meant for uh for evil God will
turn it out out for your good lifting up
sister Teresa she's asking for prayers
for DJ and family and she desperately
needs prayers for healing she was
feeling numb Lil Graham he uh gave us
not just a prayer request but also a
praise he said received good news that
my youngest niece is back home from
being in foster care ever since she's a
ever since she's been an instant infant
praise God she has been United with Mom
and asking for the other children to be
United and uh with mom as well father
May the broken altars we build and
restore the broken altars of family Lord
we unite this family Under One Roof Lord
that your love will be manifested that
your power of forgiveness your power of
Brokenness Lord will de your power to
heal Brokenness and prepare Lord the
hurts of the Pains of of lives and
choices Lord you're able and we are
lifting this a prayer request before you
as we're uh combining our faith with
that of of of the requestor uh uh matina
is asking for Sniper prayers for Warfare
in her home among her and among her
children father according to your word
Lord we can speak peace be still in the
name of Jesus PE uh peace uh be still
let peace reside in that home hush the
mouths of that that which Lord of that
chaos in the name of Jesus Lord restore
peace to that home calm those angry
Souls Lord uh uh give them Lord bring
them back into a peaceful disposition
that the God of all peace who is Christ
Jesus Lord that the peace that surpasses
that understanding Lord let it be uh
shown in this home within this family
sister Jane Smith she asked us to pray
for her family and children to follow
the lord in truth and for strength and
health as a single mom of six so that
she can do all that Jesus Lead her to do
he's able and he honors that request
because your request is that you can do
what he has called you to do in the name
of Jesus strengthen this family Lord
uplift them restore Health in the name
of Jesus help them Lord to stand on your
promises father teach them that faith
that works by love and purifies the soul
Amen in the name of Jesus strengthen
this single mother because the Lord you
said you are father to the Lord to the
widows be I'm sorry a husband to the
widows Lord be a husband to this single
mother and Lord be a father to her
children in the name of Jesus Lisa Marie
she ask for prayer for health and that
God heals from abnormalities in her body
pleas play that she's a living witness
for God thank you God heal Lord send
forth your word and heal Lord there's no
abnormality that you can't touch and
Lord restore it to to what it needs to
be that is normal father stretch forth
your Mighty powerful hand heal deliver
set free God and make Sister Lisa whole
in the name of Jesus Regina is asking us
to pray for her sister Renee uh Brothers
da situation God show your love for them
that that you have only good for them in
mind Regina is also asking us to pray
for her brother-in-law Joel for
discernment of his upcoming decision
sister benette she says please come into
agreement with me for her three sons
Greg Blake and Jacob Deliverance yes God
May their hearts and Minds be open to
accept Christ as their personal Lord and
Savior Hallelujah um Sister Lisa also is
asking us to pray forong those
injustices that makes Hearts bitter and
hateful Lord you you're able Jes says
pray that all will call upon the and
trust the Lord that we are relieved of
Oppression yes God turn those hearts oh
God we are praying oh God that those
hearts father that that evil that that
hatred Lord those feelings of Oppression
Lord and those acts of Oppression father
we pray that you rebuke it in the name
of Jesus and call these Souls into a
living Lord relationship with you Lord
we're praying for Teresa Teresa folks is
asking for prayer she says please pray
for husband uh Tim will come to the Lord
will come to know the Lord as his Savior
and that he will take his stand
Hallelujah as priest of the home that he
will take his stand as priest of the
home and father you are you are already
restoring men as priest of the home
because you have called them to be
Priests of their home leading their
family in prayer leading their family in
worship raise these men of God raise all
the men of God uh to be uh the priest of
their home Lord teach them how to be the
husband that you have called them to be
the father that you have called them
them to be the leader in their community
that you have called them to be raise
them up God in your power and strength
as you reveal your glory Lord in these
situations and circumstances of their
life praying for and Sister Sister
Charlotte Lord we're praying for her
time and Rehab praying for speedy
recovery and a soon return because we
miss our sister father we just pray for
every heart that's discouraged every
unspoken request that you're able and
you're strong and mighty to deliver
Mighty to restore Mighty to set free and
Lord as the word said when you are
forced what in the world can stand
against us when you are forced nothing
can destroy us and God you are for us
for your word say I know the plans that
I have for you sayeth the Lord and your
plans are for good and not for evil
father break break down tear down build
up Lord ReStore in the name of Jesus
heal by the power of your Mighty hand
father do the work that nobody but God
can do in the lives in the circumstances
of your people father weay pray that you
break the shackles Lord and the powers
of Darkness Lord restore your people and
call them out Lord pull them out God of
out of darkness and bring them into that
Marvelous Light and father we lift up
our pastor before your throne of grace
and mercy Lord as he prepare to bring
that Mana that Living Word that fresh
food that uncooked Lord unbaked food is
fresh it's raw and Lord raw is the best
kind father I pray that you open the
hearts of your people Lord massage these
hearts and break up the fow ground in
the name of Jesus that Lord as those
seeds fall on these hearts that that
seed will take root it falls on good
ground that it may take root that it
will grow and it will prosper in the
name of Jesus father set your lord be uh
set your glory as a rear guard before
him Lord I'm sorry as a front guard
before him a rear guard behind him and
God take care of the left and the right
side Lord uh build him up and overflow
him with the power of your anointing
Holy Spirit as it Lord just falls down
on him in the name of Jesus Lord Empower
him to speak your word to give us that
food from Heaven Lord with the anointing
power and authority that comes from
Heaven Help Us to receive all we pray
this in the Name of Christ Jesus your
son and our Lord and savior amen amen
amen amen thank you Lord
amen let us receive dead
Mana is so
sweet to trust in
Jesus just to take him at his
word just to rest upon his promise
just to
know thus sayth the
Lord Jesus
Jesus how I
trust
him how I
proved him
more oh
[Music]
Jesus Jesus
preious
Jesus Oh for Grace to trust him
more is so sweet to trust in
Jes so sweet to trust in Jesus
to take him at his
word just
to upon his
Pro just to
know the S the
Lord
Jesus
Jesus how I
trust
him how I
Pro him more
and
oh Jesus
Jesus
preious Jesus
[Music]
oh for
Grace to
trust him
more oh for
Grace to
[Music]
trust
him more
oh
[Music]
amen church happy Sabbath to you and um
I want to welcome all of you that are
viewing uh to living Mana online Church
uh today we are going to be talking
about part two of the series we just
started entitled the nine ENT Essentials
of the time of
trouble and uh last week we looked at
the First Essential which was love this
week we're going to be looking at I'm
sorry not last week uh this was the week
before we looked at the First Essential
which was love uh this week we're going
to be looking at the second essential
thing needed for the time of trouble and
so I want to invite you to pray with
me as we uh seek the Lord's face uh to
open our hearts uh for the receiving of
this message let's pray heavenly father
I want to thank you Lord for your
Amazing Grace for your love for us for
your truth and to today Lord as we open
your word please feed us the living
manner from
Heaven speak to us Lord open our hearts
and our
minds and may Our Lives be forever
changed by your word is our prayer in
Jesus name amen
amen you know
um as I was uh putting this message
together there was a character that came
to mind and actually several characters
that came to mind um thinking about this
message this part two and they're going
to be nine parts to this message by way
so so this is just part two each sermon
will be on one of these nine
Essentials um and I thought about Sam
son Samson was the strongest man that
ever lived but Samson was not the only
strong man in the Bible the Bible also
talks about David's Mighty Men and it
talks about all the Deeds that David's
Mighty Men did amazing things that they
did and as I was thinking about Samson
and and David's Mighty
Men
um it it led me to contemplate that that
at the end of time
God God's people must be as strong as
Samson not
physically not in the Physical Realm but
we must have spiritual strength that is
going to enable
us to do amazing
feats and that that was the whole theme
of the mighty man that was the whole
them
of of Samson is how strong he was and
the mighty Feats he was able to do I
want you to come with me to the Book of
Revelation chap 6 verse
17 the Bible says here for the great day
of his wrath is come and who shall be
able to stand this is the introduction
to the time of trouble and we learned in
our previous message uh part one that
this word Abel this word Abel if you
look at the screen is the word
dunami and it simply describes uh uh if
you've heard the word
dunamus right power strength who shall
be able to stand God's people are going
to need Supernatural strength to stand
in that time and and this is why the
Bible tells us in Ephesians chapter
6:10 we are being encouraged the Bible
says here finally my Brethren be strong
in the Lord and in the power of His
might only
those who are strong in the
Lord will be able to stand will be able
dunami able to stand in the time of
trouble God is calling us to be strong
but not physically strong
necessarily rather spiritually
strong and I want you to note how we get
spiritually strong again according to
the book of Ephesians chapter 3:1 16 the
Bible says that he would Grant you
according to the riches of his glory to
be strengthened with might by his spirit
in the Inner Man it is the Holy Spirit
that strengthens us it is the holy
spirit that enables us to be strong and
it would make sense that God's people
will need a special outpouring of the
holy spirit for the time of trouble
because we're going to need extra Grace
we're going to need extra strength in
this
time we know that God's people will get
this extra extra
strength God's people will be strong
because
in the Book of Daniel
11:32 we read this the Bible says and
such as do wickedly against the Covenant
shall he ultimately Satan corrupt by
flatteries but the people that do know
their God shall be
strong and do exploits put a one in the
chat if you would like to be strong put
a one in the chat if you would like to
be strong now but especially for the
time of trouble especially for the time
that is just before us God's people are
going to need to be strong and the way
that we get strong is through the spirit
and this sets the
foundation for us to understand that the
nine things needed to stand in the time
of trouble the nine things needed to be
strong in the time of trouble are right
here on the screen Galatians
5:22 reads but the fruit of the spirit
is love joy peace longsuffering
gentleness goodness Faith meekness and
Temperance against such there is no law
in our last message we talked about love
today we're gonna talk about Joy yes
joy we need to be strong in the spirit
we need to be strong in the spirit
meaning we need to be strong in these
nine things we need to be strong in
love we need to be strong in joy we need
we need to be strong in peace why
because at the time of the end the devil
is going to test your strength he's
going to see just how much love do you
really
possess come back with me to the
screen if we Now understand that one of
the nine Essentials that are needed to
stand in the time of trouble is joy we
can now begin to understand why the
Bible said in Isaiah chapter
61:3 that Jesus had been sent to appoint
unto them that mour Zion to give unto
them Beauty Beauty for Ashes the oil of
joy for mourning the Garment of Praise
for the spirit of heaviness that they
might be called Trees of Righteousness
the planting of the Lord that he might
be glorified why is
God going to give the oil of joy for
mourning the reason is
simple especially in the time of trouble
we can imagine that it's going to be a
time of great mourning it is going to be
a time of great mourning m o u r n i n g
the time of great morning which will be
followed by a time of the great morning
m o r n i n g I am looking forward to
the great morning but none of us really
look forward to the great morning I hope
yall following
me the time of trouble will be a time of
great Mourning
but we are told that the holy spirit
will be given to us it will be the oil
of Joy
particularly for a time of mourning
meaning beloved that those who make it
through the time of trouble must be
strong in Joy those who make it through
the time of trouble must be strong in
Joy they must have joy dwelling in them
the oil of joy boy must be dwelling in
them why because the Bible says in
Revelation 7 verse one after these
things I saw four Angels standing on the
four corners of the Earth holding the
Four Winds of the earth that they shall
not blow on the earth nor on the sea nor
on any
tree and I saw another Angel ascending
from the East having the Seal of the
Living God and he cried with a loud
voice to the four angels to whom it was
given to HT the earth and the Sea saying
hurt not the Earth nor the sea nor the
trees till we have sealed the Servants
of our God in their foreheads and I
heard the number of them which were
sealed and they were sealed in 140 and
4,000 of all the tribes of the children
of Israel I need you to understand that
the outpouring of the holy spirit that
the Seal of God if the holy spirit is
the one that seals the holy spirit is in
essence sealing his people with his
likeness with his character with the
fruit of the spirit meaning
when the time of trouble hits your love
is going to be tested your joy is going
to be tested your peace is going to be
tested your longsuffering is going to be
tested we're doing a sermon for every
one of these but today we're focused on
Joy listen listen when Temptation comes
in this time we are told specifically
told in the Book of James chapter 1 ver2
let's go to the screen James chapter 1
ver2 notice what the Bible says here it
says my brethren count it all joy when
you fall into diverse Temptations
knowing that the trying of your faith
worketh patience but let patience have
our perfect work that you may be perfect
and entire wanting nothing we need to
understand beloved that when that time
of trouble hits and we enter into
temptation we ought to count it all joy
now I don't know if y'all think about
this think think about that for a second
count it all joy
count it all joy when I enter into a
time of trouble the two don't even go
together a time of trouble a time of
mourning but count it all joy do you
understand that only those who are
strong in the spirit will be able to
count it all joy meaning beloved I need
to start having the joy of the Lord
right now because if I don't have it now
in the time of the footmen when things
are easy I'm definitely not going to
have joy when things get hard when the
time of trouble hits and so our prayer
through this entire message and after
this message ought to be Lord strengthen
Me In
Joy strengthen Me In Joy help me to
count it all joy when I go through
diverse Temptations
why do I need to count it
Joy why do I need to count it Joy let
Nehemiah chapter 8 ver10 tell us in
Nehemiah chapter
8:10 the Bible says the joy of the Lord
is your strength did y'all catch
that did yall catch that just now the
joy of the Lord is your strength
who the great day of his wrath has come
and who shall be able to
stand only those who are strong in the
spirit only those who are strong in love
only those who are strong in Joy the
Bible just told us that the joy of the
Lord is your
strength so if I'm going to endure
through the time of trouble my joy must
endure through that time of trouble my
love must endure through that time of
trouble the Bible literally tells us in
Matthew Chapter 13 Mark chap 13:3 it
says and you shall be hated of all men
for my name sake but he that shall
endure unto the end the same shall be
saved so I need you to understand that
what this is saying is not that he that
endures like you know you escaped
escaped the prison you got to the
mountains and you were able to hide away
from the police you know we're not
talking about enduring that weight we're
talking about enduring
spiritually those who
endure in jooy despite what is going on
around
them they are the ones that are sealed
they are the ones that are saved and
thus our prayer ought to be Lord teach
me me to have joy in the midst of my
crisis I need you to understand beloved
that Jesus is our example y'all are
already a step ahead of me I already see
the verse going in the chat let's look
at it on the screen notice what the
Bible says in Hebrews
12:2 it says looking unto Jesus the
author and finisher of our faith
who for the joy that was set before him
endured the
cross how did Jesus endure his time of
trouble how did he endure the cross how
did he endure the crisis it was because
of the joy that was set before him
meaning then if I want to endure my
crisis I need to have the joy of the
Lord that enabled him to endure his
crisis y'all put a one in the chat put a
one in the chat if you understood what I
just said the joy of the Lord okay watch
this not the joy of Ivor not the joy of
Jackie not the joy of Esther not the joy
of vernett not the joy of lvan not the
joy of nky not the joy of Marco not the
joy of Terry not the joy of of of lonia
no no no no the joy of the Lord is your
strength
so then if I want strength now and in
the time of trouble I have to have the
joy of the Lord and that Joy is the same
joy that en enabled the Lord to endure
his own
trial the Bible says it was for the joy
that was set before him in other words
Jesus looked before him and he was like
that Joy right there that is worth
everything I'm going through right
now that Joy right there that is worth
the trial the tri that is worth
everything and that Joy kept him going
in his time of trouble what was that Joy
let's see what the Bible says Psalms 1
Psalm 16:9 and 10 the Bible says this
therefore my heart is
glad and my glory
rejoiceth My Flesh also shall Rest In
Hope for thou will not leave my soul in
Hell neither Willl thou suffer thine
Holy One to see
corruption thou will show me the path of
life in thy presence is fullness of joy
at thy right hand there are Pleasures
forever more did y'all see what the joy
of the Lord is right this verse is a
prophecy pointing forward to Jesus
remember thou will not leave my soul in
Hell thou will not leave me in the grave
this was referencing Jesus himself so
now we see exactly what the joy of the
Lord was the joy of the Lord the joy of
Jesus was that in his father's presence
was fullness of
joy that is what he looked forward to he
looked forward to a Heavenly reality and
that Heavenly reality
enabled
him to persevere through the challenges
that he faced while living on this
Earth that was the joy of the Lord Acts
chapter 2 verse 28 puts it the same way
thou has made me to know thou has made
known to me the ways of
life Thou shalt make me full of joy with
thy countenance it is a countenance of
God it is the presence of God that is
the ultimate joy of the Lord the Lord
was
enabled to go through his crisis because
he had his eyes set on Heavenly things
the Bible tells us that this also was
his Joy you see it was not just the
presence of his father that was the joy
of the Lord but listen to what the Bible
says in Psalms 5 I'm sorry Isaiah 53:1
the Bible says of Jesus he shall see of
the travail of his soul and shall be
satisfied by his knowledge shall my
righteous servant justify many for he
shall bear their
iniquities do you see
this the joy of the
Lord was in seeing redeemed people
people in
heaven
wow it was that
Joy I am doing this I am going through
this
crisis and I'm enduring these things
because the joy that is set before me is
to see my father and to see my people
United together
living together forever in all eternity
there is nothing that makes me
happier than to see you saved now hold
on for a second I want you to just think
about this for a
moment you just
read that the thing that makes the god
of the universe
happiest is your presence in
heaven now I know that as a Christian
you may have walked through your
Christian experience thinking man God is
trying to find ways that I will be lost
or man God is you know I if I'm saved
I'll be the happy one no no no no no no
no y'all don't understand how many of
you have a joy something that you love
to do like oh man this thing makes me
happy I want you to take that joy that
you have your ultimate joy and multiply
that Joy by
infinity and I want you to get this
thought in your mind if you
can
that
joy that is the
joy that God
has over
you and beloved if nothing else in this
world strengthens you that thought that
you are the joy of the Lord should
strengthen you like nothing else did
y'all get that just
now you are the joy of the
Lord you are why Jesus endured the
suffering and so as you begin to
contemplate this and you're going
through your own time of trouble you
cannot in your mind you're like man is
god with me does God love me you need to
understand that the joy of the Lord was
you
and when you understand that the joy of
the Lord was you the joy of the Lord is
you and you being in
heaven beloved that's going to make you
endure that's G to that's going to lead
you to endure in ways you never thought
possible that joy of the Lord knowing
that the joy of the Lord is you in
heaven you would think the joy of the
Lord might be some otherworldly you know
I really really like this is God but no
God says the thing that I am Overjoyed
of the most is you being in heaven with
me Paul I'm sorry um let's go to
Zephaniah chapter 3 verse 17 I want you
to note what the Bible says the Lord thy
God is in the midst of thee in the midst
of thee is mighty he will
save he will rejoice over thee with joy
he will rest in his love he will Joy
over thee with
singing are y'all catching
this the joy of the Lord is your
strength meaning when you understand
just when you understand that you are
the joy of the Lord something about that
strengthens you something about that
makes us go wait God loves me that much
that I am his Joy you mean he wants to
see me in heaven he's doing everything
in his power to save me short of forcing
me when you understand this beloved you
begin to also understand you will also
understand why in 1 Thessalonians
chapter 2:19 the Bible says for what is
our hope our joy our crown of rejoicing
are not even ye in the presence of our
Lord Jesus Christ at his coming the joy
of the Saints is the same joy as the
Lord
the joy of the Saints is looking forward
to that day when all the redeemed stand
in the presence of Jesus saved in fact
here's how Ellen White put it in the
great controversy page 647 she says this
with unutterable love Jesus welcomes his
faithful ones to the joy of their lord
the savior's Joy is in seeing in the
Kingdom of
Glory the souls that have been saved by
his Agony and
humiliation and the redeemed will be
sharers in this joy as they behold among
the Blessed those who have been W to
Christ through their prayers their
labors and loving
sacrifice as they gather about the great
white Throne gladness unspeakable will
fill their hearts when they behold Those
whom they have won for Christ and see
that one one has gained others and these
still others all brought into the Haven
of Rest there to lay their crowns at
jesus' feet and praise him through
endless cycles of Eternity that is
powerful y'all that is
powerful that the joy of the Lord
becomes our
joy the joy of the Lord becomes our joy
when we see the redeemed standing in
heaven and we see those that we have led
through the grace of Christ to the
kingdom of heaven the joy of the Lord
beloved is your strength now watch this
this is further Amplified the fact that
this is this is the joy of the Lord is
going to now allow you to see a verse
that you know well in a whole new
light put a one in the chat if you ready
to see something in a whole new light
are y'all ready check this out y'all
the Bible says in Ephesians chapter 4
and verse
30 grieve not the holy spirit of God
whereby you are sealed unto the day of
Redemption all
right
what grieve not let me read it again and
grieve not the spirit the holy spirit of
God whereby you are sealed unto the day
of
redemption what does it
mean to grieve the spirit of God that
word grieve it literally
means to
distress ref reflectively or L to be
sad all right
see before when you read this verse
before when you read this verse you
thought probably grieving the spirit of
God meant oh you made me mad now yeah
yeah yeah you made me mad now I'm
leaving you made me mad I'm leaving
that's not what the text is saying what
the text is saying is liter literally
what we have seen you are making God sad
why because what you're saying is I
don't want to be in heaven with
you I would rather do my own thing and
beloved this makes the spirit of God sad
so think about it now the opposite of
joy is
sadness the Bible says don't grieve or
make sad the spirit it's not a threat
it's a
plea please don't do this to me please
don't make me sad if you if you cut
yourself off from me I am going to be
sad and when you understand beloved that
you are so important to Jesus to the
spirit to the father that by stepping
away from him you make him sad there's
something in that where you're like you
know what nah no I'm not going to make
you sad no no no no I'm going to
be wow I am your
joy that thought in and of itself
beloved is such a
powerful Divine
motivator but only those who understand
the joy of the Lord only those who who
embrace the joy of the Lord
are strengthened by
it when we reject the spirit beloved we
are robbing the spirit of his Joy which
is
you think that through when we reject
the spirit we are robbing the spirit of
his Joy which is you the spirit is sad
because you're saying I I don't I don't
want to follow
you I don't want to follow your
leadings come on this is why Psalm 51:
10-12 uh David wrote create create in me
a clean heart oh God and renew a right
Spirit Within Me cast me not away from
thy presence and take not thy Holy
Spirit from me restore unto me the what
the joy of your
salvation beloved when God's people are
sealed at the end of time when God's
people are sealed during that time of
trouble before that time of trouble
they are sealed in love they are sealed
in
Joy the joy of Salvation cannot be taken
away from them so when the enemy comes
trying to test their Joy trying to make
everything around them in such a
condition that that he expects they will
walk through with no joy and beloved let
me tell you I just saw it in the chat
listen there is a reason I believe that
the enemy is seeking to to bring such a
state of depression in the
world there is a
reason he's trying to
steal people's Joy he's trying to steal
your happiness he want the the thief
cometh to to kill steal and destroy
listen the Bible says in Revelation 14
verse1 and I looked and lo a lamb stood
on the Mount Zion with him 140 4,000
having his father's name written in
their foreheads why am I poting this
verse out to you because I want you to
check this out in connection with Isaiah
51:11 which says therefore the redeemed
of the Lord shall return and come with
singing onto Zion let's go back
144,000 standing on Mount Zion with the
lamb let's go forward therefore redeem
the Lord shall return with coming with
come with singing unto Zion and
everlasting what Joy shall be upon their
heads they shall obtain gladness and joy
and sorrow and mourning shall flee
away who are the redeemed that stand on
Mount Zion those who experienced the joy
of the Lord you know what I like about
that verse it says sorrow and mourning
shall flee away I want you to imagine it
like this
right
imagine imagine cheetah don't don't you
know a cheatah can't kill you anymore
right and you really like cheaters and
you'd like to go pet a cheetah one day
but the Cheetahs are so fast that every
time you make a step to like go try to
get the cheetah the cheetah takes off
and there's no hope of you ever catching
the
cheetah now I want you to exchange that
cheetah for an animal called s
and
mourning when the text says sorrow and
mourning shall flee away not that you
would want to chase sorrow or chase
mourning but just imagine if you
did if you were like you know what let
me see if I can catch morning let me see
if I can catch some sorrow in heaven you
will never be able to catch morning or
it just fleas you can't I man I can
never get a hold of that
thing and that's not a reason to be sad
y'all the only the only response to that
is well if there's no mourning or sorrow
the only option I have is
Joy how many of you would like that the
only option you have is
Joy because mourning and sorrow are
always fleeing away from
you yes that's in heaven that's in
heaven but you know what on Earth we can
to begin to experience that even in the
presence of morning and and sorrow so on
Earth while mourning and sorrow may not
leave us we can have the joy of the Lord
a joy that passes understanding in the
midst of our
crisis are y'all with me so far come on
let's go let's go I need you to
understand this beloved that Joy is a
place I don't know if you ever thought
about that but joy is a place the Bible
says in Matthew 25:23 his lord said unto
him well done good and faithful servant
thou has been faith fful over few things
I will make thee ruler over many things
enter thou into the joy of the Lord do
y'all did y'all see
that that enter thou into the joy of the
Lord that's a
place God is calling the Kingdom of
Heaven the joy of the Lord enter thou
into the joy of the Lord that's a
place when we enter into heaven we are
entering into the joy of the Lord and
Psalms 48:2 uh Bears this out beautiful
for situation the joy of the whole earth
is Mount Zion the on the sides of the
north the city of the great king the joy
of the Lord is a
place where when you enter into it there
is
tangible Joy you can feel it in the
air sadness and mourning flee away
here and beloved that thought alone and
the fact that God wants you in that
place
that's the joy of the Lord right there
wow man what okay so yeah I'm going
through this and yeah I'm experienc this
in a time of trouble but the joy of the
Lord that which has been set before me
is my strength and I will keep my eyes
focused upon that joy of the Lord so
that while everything around me is
mourning and sorrow and while I'm going
through this time of trouble my eye has
been fixed on that Heavenly City my eye
has been fixed on the king of glory my
eye has been fixed on that place called
Joy because Joy is a
place the gospel beloved is ultimately
our joy note with me in Matthew chapter
13:44 Matthew in fact Isaiah 51:3 first
for the Lord shall Comfort Zion he will
Comfort all her Wast place places and he
will make her Wilderness like Eden and
her desert like the garden of the Lord
joy and gladness shall be found therein
Thanksgiving and the voice of Melody man
what a listen y'all what a
place what a place that joy and gladness
are found in
it listen in the Book of Matthew chapter
13:44 the Bible says again the Kingdom
of Heaven is like unto a treasure hid in
the field which when a man has found he
hideth and for Joy thereof goeth and sth
all that he has that he may buy the
field do you understand that those who
sell all that they have to buy the field
are those who see the joy set ahead of
them they see that joy and they're like
yep it's worth it I'm willing to sell
everything I have for that which is
coming for that which is coming the
Bible tells us in John in Jeremiah 15:16
thy words were found and I did eat them
and Thy Word was unto me the joy and
rejoicing of mine heart I need you to
understand the word of God is your
joy because it is in the word of God
that all these promises are explained it
is in the word of God that this Joy is
explained it is in the word of God that
we discover that the joy of Jesus was us
ourselves we are his greatest joy Joy I
want you to imagine everything that
Divinity can experience and of all those
things Jesus says you are my altar you
are above every other joy that I have
beloved that is an amazing and
mindblowing thought the Bible tells us
in John 15:9 as the father has loved me
so I have loved you continue ye in my
love if you keep my Commandments you
shall abide in my love even as I have
kept my father's Commandments and abide
in his love these things I have spoken
unto you that my joy might remain in you
and that your joy might be full let me
break it down for you Jesus wants us to
know that the way the father loves
him is the way that he loves
us and he says that ought to make your
joy
full that ought to make your joy full
and make you
joyful the exact love my father has for
me is the exact love I have for
you please think about that please
understand the significance of that when
we dwell on the joy of the Lord
something will begin to happen in our
hearts John in the Book of John 16 and22
it says again and you know therefore you
now therefore have sorrow but I will see
you again and your heart shall rejoice
and your joy no man taketh away when
Jesus was resurrected from the grave he
said when you see me again when you
understand that I am in that place right
now that I'm
alive and that I will bring you here you
will have a joy that no man can take
from you you will have a joy that no man
can steal from you this is why Jude 1:24
says now unto him that is is able to
keep you from falling and to present you
faultless before the presence before his
presence before the presence of his
glory
with exceeding
Joy with exceeding Joy now beloved
listen to me come on we're getting ready
to to to to close this up listen to me
the time of trouble is a time like none
other the Bible says here but
rejoice in as much as you are partakers
of Christ sufferings that when his glory
shall be revealed you may be glad also
with exceeding
Joy when the suffering
comes
Rejoice that's what God tells us you
cannot do that if your joy is not strong
enough and your joy will not be strong
enough to take you through the time of
trouble it must be the joy of the Lord
listen in Matthew 7:24 the the Bible
says now therefore he whosoever Hearth
these sayings of mine and doeth them I
will liken him unto a wise man which
built his house upon a rock and the rain
descended and the floods came and the
winds blew and beat upon that house and
it fell not for it was founded upon a
rock the devil is going to come and try
to test your
joy he's going to bring everything he
possibly can against you to test the
strength of your joy but I need you to
see this as we close by by looking at
the example of Jesus I need you to
understand something the Bible says of
Jesus he is despised and rejected of men
a Man of Sorrows listen to me y'all
Jesus was a Man of Sorrows and
acquainted with grief why did he become
a Man of Sorrows why was he acquainted
with grief listen to what the text says
and we hid as it were our faces from him
he was despised and we esteemed him not
surely he has borne our griefs and
carried our sorrows yet we did esteem
him stricken smitten of God and
Afflicted he was wounded for our
transgression he was bruised for our
iniquities the chastisement of our peace
was upon him and with his stripes we are
healed all we like sheep have gone
astray we have turned everyone to his
own way and the lord has laid on him the
iniquity of us all he was oppressed and
he was afflicted yet he open not his
mouth he is brought as a lamb to the
slaughter and as a sheep before her
Sherer is dumb so he opened not his
mouth he was taken from prison and from
judgment and who shall declare his
generation for he was cut off out of the
land of the living for the transgression
of my people was he stricken now watch
this he made his grave with the wicked
and with the rich in his death because
he had done no violence neither was any
deceit found in his mouth yet it pleased
the Lord to bruise him he has put him to
grief when thou shalt make his soul an
offering for sin he shall see his seed
he shall prolong his days and the
pleasure of the Lord shall prosper in
his hand watch this watch
this do y'all understand that everything
Jesus went through he became a man of
sorrow and a man of grief he became all
these things for the joy that was set
before
him how was Jesus able to endure all
that he
endured it was for the joy that was set
before
him listen listen check this
out but when Jesus said unto him Judas
betrays thou the son of man with a
kiss this is how for the joy that was
set before him he could be
betrayed and still have
joy he could be betrayed and still have
joy in Mark
14:50 the Bible says that all his
disciples they all forsook him and
fled he could be forsaken of his
disciples and still have joy in John
18:12 then the band and the captains and
officers of the Jews took him and bound
him he could be falsely imprisoned and
still have joy in Mark 1457 and 58 there
arose certain and bare false witness
against him saying we heard him say I
will destroy this Temple that is made
with hands and within three days I will
build another made without hands yes he
could be falsely accused and still have
joy in Matthew 27 verse 26 to 29 then
released he barabus unto them and when
he had scorched Jesus and delivered him
to be crucified they stripped him and
put on him a Scarlet robe and when they
had ploted a crown of thorns they put it
upon his head and a re in his right hand
and they bowed the KNE before him and
mocked him saying hail King of the Jews
and they spit upon him and they took the
Reed and smote him on the head and after
that they had mocked him they took the
robe off from him and put on his own
reignment and led him away to crucify
him Jesus could be mocked Jesus could be
spat Upon Jesus could be rejected by the
public Jesus could be could be beaten
and yet he still had Joy the Bible says
and they crucified him and parted his
garments casting lots that it might be
fulfilled which was spoken by the
prophet they parted my garments among
among them and upon my vesture they did
cast lots Jesus could be crucified and
still have joy let me tell you something
in the time of
trouble God's people are going to be
falsely accused in the time of trouble
God's people are going to be mocked in
the time of trouble God's people are
going to be falsely imprisoned in the
time of trouble God's people are going
to be spat upon in the time of trouble
God's people are going to be beaten in
the time of trouble God's people are
going to go through all kinds of
craziness but if we behold Jesus who was
our example and see that it was for the
joy that was set before
him that he was able to endure the cross
despise the shame then we know ah if I
want to make it through the time of
trouble I have to have the joy of the
Lord because the joy of the Lord is my
strength and in order for me to be able
to stand I've got to be strong enough to
stand I got it Lord I got it help me to
have the joy of the Lord because the
Bible tells us in Daniel 12:1 at that
time Michael shall stand up the great
Prince which standeth for the children
of thy people and there will be a time
of trouble such as never was since there
was a nation even to that same time and
at that time thy people shall be
delivered everyone that shall be found
written in the book If I desire to make
it through this time of trouble Lord I'm
going to need to be strong in Joy
so let me never forget this verse
looking onto Jesus the author and
finisher of our faith who for the joy
that was set before him endured the
cross despising the shame and is sat
down at the right hand of the Throne of
God
god listen to
me
Jesus says I will give you my
joy and that
Joy will be more powerful than anything
the world can bring against
you our prayer ought to be today Lord
give me your joy
let my joy be full let me understand and
grasp the the reality that the joy of
the Lord is my strength the nine
essential things that I need for the
time of trouble we've covered to the
first is love the next is Joy put that
one in the chat if you want that joy to
be filled to be in you so that nothing
can take it away put that one in the
chat as we close in prayer heavenly
father thank you thank you Lord for your
Amazing Grace thank you for the
joy that was set before you and thank
you for helping us to understand that
that Joy was us we are your joy and so
Lord teach us to understand this and to
embrace it so that our joy might be
fulfilled Lord grant us this
essential not only for the time of
trouble but even for our time right now
please
Lord grant us your joy and we thank you
for your amazing Joy Over
Us in Jesus name we pray amen and amen
we're going to put the link in the chat
for the altar live we encourage you to
join us uh we're going to have a
discussion about uh uh uh the Sabbath
school and about uh the sermon this is
where we get together after church so
please uh feel free to join us on the
altar live link may God bless you and
may the joy of the Lord be your strength
amen and
amen thank you for joining us today if
this is your first time worshiping with
us please check out our website at
Living mana. Church we are not just here
for Sabbath service we have weekly
programming too that covers mental
health physical health weekly prayer
service Financial Health and proving the
existence of God it is our desire that
our programming will continue to bless
you please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the Gospel of Jesus Christ
[Music]
e